<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>Blog of Chris Gallo | Sharing what I learn because it pays to be curious.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Bargain for Bugs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*zjcT_Fy9Gh1BpsWfAMQ0PQ.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Comic from &lt;a href=&quot;https://xkcd.com/1163/&quot;&gt;xkcd.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I found a bug . . .&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you receive an email from a customer that starts like this, what is your
first reaction?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disappointed? Are you anxious? Shocked?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The support team at &lt;a href=&quot;https://highrisehq.com/&quot;&gt;Highrise&lt;/a&gt; is often &lt;strong&gt;skeptical&lt;/strong&gt;.
Why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because sometimes what you think is a bug isn’t a bug at all. It’s an
&lt;strong&gt;expectation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re firm believers that the &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@cjgallo/the-best-answer-is-a-question-a5484265cc70&quot;&gt;best answer is a
question&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because if you expected &lt;em&gt;X&lt;/em&gt;, and got *Y *— that’s not a bug. It’s an
expectation. What did you expect to happen is a powerful question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;for-example----&quot;&gt;For example . . . .&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I found a bug. When I filter by the tag  and I only see four total contacts.
There are several other people associated with the companies tagged  so why does
it only show four?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Please advise on when this will be fixed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was an email our support team received over and over again. When we began
asking the question: What are you expecting to happen?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We found that the customer expected to filter by the tag , and for that filter
to include all people contacts that belong to companies tagged  too. However,
this isn’t how Highrise was built to work at the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless, you also tagged all the people contacts with , your filter won’t include
those people contacts. Only the company contacts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This wasn’t a bug afterall. Highrise was working as it was intended in this
example. The problem was that intention didn’t match most customers’
expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was an email our support team received over and over again. This isn’t a
bug. It’s only a difference in expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This failure of expectations led to our team to make an adjustment. Instead of
the intention to only include people if they have the same tag, our team made it
so if people contacts belong to a company contact, those people contacts inherit
those same tags. We call it &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.highrisehq.com/contacts/better-tags/#company-tags&quot;&gt;company
tags&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*WLQeor2ic-fVL1oFMup1tA.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;figcaption_hack&quot;&gt;Not a bug, but a failed expectation led us to improve Highrise using company
tags.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not here to argue the definition of a bug. Or to make a case that bugs don’t
exist in Highrise. Or to say if a customer assumes there is a bug, that they’re
wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, they’re not wrong. And bugs exist in all software too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All I’m suggesting is before giving in and adding to your bug report, ask a
question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are you expecting to happen?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you need to track leads and manage follow-ups, please check out &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://highrisehq.com/&quot;&gt;Highrise&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Your address book doesn’t do enough, other CRM software tries to do too much. Highrise is built to do just what you need — no more, no less.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/bargain-for-bugs/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/bargain-for-bugs/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Do the opposite</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When you ask people, ‘What’s the opposite of fragile?,’ they tend to say robust, resilient, adaptable, solid, strong. That’s not it. The opposite of fragile is something that gains from disorder. —  Nassim Nicholas Taleb, &lt;a href=&quot;http://people.hotdogsandeggs.com/nassim-nicholas-taleb&quot;&gt;Antifragile&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So much of our lives is follow the leader. We do the same things because other people do it. Copycat society. Same? Same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I’ve found one of the most useful things you can do is the exact opposite sometimes. Here are three examples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cold-calls-at-night&quot;&gt;Cold calls at night?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his book, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Tools-Titans-Billionaires-World-Class-Performers/dp/1328683788&quot;&gt;Tools of Titans&lt;/a&gt;, Tim Ferriss describes how he failed in a sales job over and over again. He was smiling and dialing, and failing. A lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He realized all the other salespeople made their cold emails and calls between business hours, 9 am to 5 pm. And then he asked himself . . .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“What if I did the opposite of all the other sales guys, just for 48 hours? I decided to take a Thursday and Friday and make sales calls only from 7 to 8:30 a.m. and 6 to 7:30 p.m. For the rest of the day, I focused on cold emails. It worked like &lt;strong&gt;gangbusters&lt;/strong&gt;. The big boss often picked up the phone directly.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ferriss continued this experiment by not pitching a product, but just asking questions. He also studied the technical aspects of the product to sound more like an engineer and less like a salesperson.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He ended emails with &lt;em&gt;I totally understand if you’re too busy to reply, and thank you for reading this far&lt;/em&gt; instead of generic replies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it worked. He outsold the entire office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;noon-years&quot;&gt;Noon-Years&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a social example. This past New Year’s Eve, my friends and I wanted to get together to do something. But New Year’s fell on a Saturday. This meant going out would be crowded. And expensive (time and money wise).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what did we do instead?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good friend of mine suggested we do the opposite. Let’s celebrate at noon. Not at midnight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hosted some friends at our place, my wife made breakfast that turned into a brunch. We even counted down with old YouTube videos from past New Year’s at noon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day was a big hit. I was in bed by 9 pm, and still had tons of fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;un-document&quot;&gt;Un-Document&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A product example of doing the opposite comes from Snapchat. When the video app launched, it did one thing the exact opposite than other social competitors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitter archives anything you tweet. Facebook has photo albums of you from 2006. But Snapchat?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it was first released, whatever you posted, disappeared after a short period of time. Poof. You couldn’t find it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a online moment that felt like a moment in reality. When you talk to your friend or see them out and about, those moments disappear. This made &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.garyvaynerchuk.com/the-snap-generation-a-guide-to-snapchats-history/&quot;&gt;separated Snapchat&lt;/a&gt; from other social networks early on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It does the opposite in other areas too, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://m.signalvnoise.com/the-intimidating-zero-4d90fcdcc3b2&quot;&gt;not showing follower counts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes doing the same thing as everyone else is fragile. The slightest missteps can trip you up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The opposite is antifragile. Making cold calls at night, celebrating New Year’s at noon instead of midnight, and sharing a video that disappears are all examples that led to good results. Each one got better with disorder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If something isn’t working for you, ask yourself one question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if I did the opposite?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you dig this post, you might enjoy reading &lt;a href=&quot;http://people.hotdogsandeggs.com/nassim-nicholas-taleb&quot;&gt;Nassim Nicholas Taleb&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Tools-Titans-Billionaires-World-Class-Performers/dp/1328683788&quot;&gt;Tim Ferriss&lt;/a&gt; too.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/do-the-opposite/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/do-the-opposite/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Jousting with Jekyll</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One responsibility of the support team here at &lt;a href=&quot;https://highrisehq.com/&quot;&gt;Highrise&lt;/a&gt; is to maintain our Extras page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s the &lt;a href=&quot;https://highrisehq.com/extras/&quot;&gt;Extras page&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a list of all the 3rd party products that integrate with Highrise. Almost
all were built by the 3rd party using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/basecamp/highrise-api&quot;&gt;Highrise API&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This page is important for current and future customers because people use more
than one product to get their work done. And these integrations can often save
people tons of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it became an absolute pain to manage for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a whopping 63 different listings on the Extras page right now. Requests to add new listings, update current listings, and remove old listings started to add up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Highrise marketing site is maintained using the static-site generator &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. It gives our team control over our content, it works fast, and it’s not a feature heavy dynamic CMS like Wordpress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll is simple. And powerful . . . if you know how to use that power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Extras page was just a giant HTML page in Jekyll. All listings were written in HTML, and if you needed to update a listing, you had to edit the repetitive
HTML file and find exactly what line needed to be updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This led to manual errors. Typos in HTML. Incorrect links. A lot of wasted time to make tiny changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/datafiles/&quot;&gt;Jekyll data files&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data files give a middle finger to repetition. You can set custom options and load custom data to make your life much easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;here-is-a-short-video-of-why-we-made-this-change-with-an-example&quot;&gt;Here is a short video of why we made this change with an example:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;wistia_responsive_padding&quot; style=&quot;padding:56.25% 0 0 0;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wistia_responsive_wrapper&quot; style=&quot;height:100%;left:0;position:absolute;top:0;width:100%;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://fast.wistia.net/embed/iframe/mfurfld6bh?videoFoam=true&quot; title=&quot;Wistia video player&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; class=&quot;wistia_embed&quot; name=&quot;wistia_embed&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; oallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; msallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;https://fast.wistia.net/assets/external/E-v1.js&quot; async=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-to-use-data-files-in-jekyll&quot;&gt;How to use data files in Jekyll&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
First, create a folder in your repo titled &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_data&lt;/code&gt; and save it. This is where you’re going to store your files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Files can be in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.yml, .yaml, .json, or .csv&lt;/code&gt; format. We’re using &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.yml&lt;/code&gt; in our example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, create a file you want to store in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_data&lt;/code&gt; folder. We’ve created the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;highrises.yml&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an example of one of our data files in format:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
    - name: Highrise iPhone App
      link: https://highrisehq.com/apps/ios
      image: extras/img_iphone_app.png
      description: Collaborate on contacts, notes, and tasks all from your iPhone.
    - name: Android
      link: https://highrisehq.com/apps/android
      image: extras/img_android_app.png
      description: Collaborate on contacts, notes, and tasks all from your Android.
      &lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The data can now be accessed using in our HTML. The filename &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;highrises.yml&lt;/code&gt; determines the
variable name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This information can now be used in your templates or HTML files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;https://gist.github.com/gallochris/a583994674eee7426896040e98de74d2.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using  in our file, Jekyll will insert the information from the data file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/1*7u5mIbo41YC9u_zwvBjSew.png&quot; alt=&quot;Jekyll Example&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data files have saved us lots of time here at Highrise. Other examples of where
you might use them:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;accessing different authors’ bios of your blog&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;posting store hours for your brick-and-mortar shop&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ordering any list of products you’re selling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in learning Jekyll, we recommend checking out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/tutorials/home/&quot;&gt;tutorials here&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;community here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was orginally published on Basecamp’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://m.signalvnoise.com/jousting-with-jekyll-20687ceea042&quot;&gt;Signal v Noise&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/jousting-with-jekyll/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/jousting-with-jekyll/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Data is man-made</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s a secret from the support team at Highrise. Customer support metrics make us feel icky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our team doesn’t know our satisfaction score. We’ve never asked any of the people that use Highrise to try those types of surveys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can’t give you an exact number for our average response time. It depends. Sometimes it’s 90 seconds, and other times it’s within 24 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can’t tell you our average handle time for an issue. Our team has a general idea, but no exact number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These types of customer support metrics aren’t wrong. We’re sure they work for other support teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re just not sure they’re right for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because there is one piece of knowledge we’ve come to realize: &lt;strong&gt;data is man-made&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-do-you-mean-data-is-man-made&quot;&gt;What do you mean data is man-made?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data or metrics or stats are all man-made. A human decides what to measure, how to measure it, how to present it, and how to share it with others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But why does it matter to measure these things? &lt;a href=&quot;https://m.signalvnoise.com/real-time-dashboards-considered-harmful-7ab026942ac#.ssz9jaflz&quot;&gt;And what’s the point?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of times people avoid these questions when it comes to data. Companies copy what other teams measure, ignoring the fact if it’s important to measure the same things in the same way, or if it’s even important to measure it at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;but-isnt-all-data-objective&quot;&gt;But isn’t all data objective?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Many people view numerical data as more trustworthy than qualitative data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Clayton Christensen, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Competing-Against-Luck-Innovation-Customer/dp/0062435612&quot;&gt;Competing Against Luck&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Numbers are black and white. Concrete. You can trust the numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nope. Almost all data is built on biases and judgement. Because humans are deciding what to measure, how to measure, and why to measure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Numbers fit perfectly into a spreadsheet or a graph. A number gives a &lt;em&gt;definitive&lt;/em&gt; answer to questions like how much or how many.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That doesn’t mean you should treat those numbers as &lt;em&gt;insights&lt;/em&gt; and act immediately. Data shouldn’t be used to prove a point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data should be used to fuel your imagination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;words--numbers&quot;&gt;Words &amp;gt; Numbers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Qualitative data isn’t easy. There aren’t any formulas or simple math. It doesn’t fit into a spreadsheet. It doesn’t answer questions. It’s not black and white.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s colorful. Messy. Qualitative data creates more questions. It’s not simple to present or share with others. It takes some time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our support team has found one thing to be true. Qualitative data is worth it. 100 percent worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, our team recently &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.highrisehq.com/post/153354155666/filter-ui-updates&quot;&gt;updated the filters in Highrise&lt;/a&gt;. This update was to an earlier revision to filters we made during the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t driven by one piece of data. One piece of quantitative data. It came from a new user:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thanks for pointing out those filters. I didn’t even know they were there. Those icons weren’t obvious to me at first.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This hit all of us across the nose. The filters looked better, aesthetically it was a much more clean than the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cl.ly/2S3V332N281E&quot;&gt;previous design&lt;/a&gt;. But how to use the filters wasn’t as obvious any longer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Folks need to find a specific set of contacts in the &lt;em&gt;city of: Chicago&lt;/em&gt;, that have the &lt;em&gt;value: Interested&lt;/em&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;custom field: Status&lt;/em&gt;, and that are &lt;em&gt;tagged: Potential&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t clear how to do that, so our team made a change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://draftin.com:443/images/48870?token=KjKIKSoBT_Eeuyaeb9xQH-9UNDo45bUXPPtz6jse9AG4I84q0exg0u6CtEPBFQmB-fVA958PC72ZeTS2TJVW_q8&quot; alt=&quot;new-old-filters.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quantitative data didn’t tell us we needed to make this change. It was all qualitative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questions from customers and questions from our team. It was a conversation. There is not a numerical value you can put on that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-what-do-we-measure&quot;&gt;So what do we measure?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of striving to lower our average response time or improve our customer satisfaction score, our support team is aiming for something a bit different. Something harder to measure. It’s not a number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alisongroves&quot;&gt;Alison&lt;/a&gt; would say, we strive to put ourselves out of work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t confuse that with us not wanting to work at Highrise. We love it, and love working with our small team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we mean is we want to make it easier for people to use Highrise. We want to create a product that is so obvious and so easy to use that we seldom get questions on how to use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when folks do have questions, we want to have resources available to them right away, so they can help themselves. So if someone has a question at 2 am in the morning, and we’re not around, they can find an answer without waiting for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because we don’t believe managing a number is going to improve our support. We believe focusing on customers and what they are trying to do with Highrise is going to make a better product, and better support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please don’t take this as gospel. What works for our team, might not work for your team. And vice versa.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chapter 9 of Clayton Christensen’s recent book, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Competing-Against-Luck-Innovation-Customer/dp/0062435612&quot;&gt;Competing Against Luck&lt;/a&gt;, was a big inspiration for this post. The entire book is great, and you should check it out.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/data-is-man-made/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/data-is-man-made/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Customer Can be You</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eater.com/2015/6/8/8745361/chef-roger-verge-died&quot;&gt;Roger Vergé&lt;/a&gt; was a world-renowned chef. He won the Michelin star for his restaurant, Moulin de Mougins, three times and countless other awards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shep_Gordon&quot;&gt;Shep Gordon&lt;/a&gt;, Vergé’s manager, described him as the first person he ever met that had true success. He was a master as his craft, and truly happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gordon shares a story with &lt;a href=&quot;http://chiseler.org/post/145157416821/life-after-supermensch-an-interview-with-shep&quot;&gt;The Chiseler&lt;/a&gt; about going out to eat with Vergé. The long-time manager estimates that he ate roughly 1,000 meals with him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what’s it like eating with a world class chef?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I remember one time the food was horrible,” Gordon shares. “I ate half of my plate. He finished his plate and my plate. When we left the restaurant, I said, ‘Did you really think it that was good?’ And he said, ‘Oh Shep, it was horrible.’ But he ate every bit of it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why would Vergé do that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the Thanksgiving holiday, I spent a good chunk of my time traveling alongside many other people. For some reason, I was more observant in my travels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you travel, you often hire many services and interact with lots of people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might take an Uber or Lyft to the airport. Go through security and interact with TSA. Board a plane with other passengers. Deal with flight attendants. Rental car agencies. Hotel concierges. Waiters at restaurants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When traveling, you’re a constant customer of different services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t until recently, where I began to notice how people were treating the folks providing these services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the consequences of working in customer support almost every day is that you gain perspective on being a customer. Here’s 3 lessons I’ve learned on how to be a kinder customer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;share-more-information&quot;&gt;Share more information&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Help me, help you. It’s true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need assistance from someone, it’s important to explain exactly what you want to accomplish and where you’re struggling in trying to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because the &lt;a href=&quot;http://supportops.co/dont-be-a-robot-create-conversations/&quot;&gt;best answer is often a question&lt;/a&gt; for someone trying to help you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can eliminate those questions by providing information up front, it’s a win-win for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, contacting support and saying, “everything is missing, please advise,” isn’t all that helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It generates more questions for the person providing support, which can lead to lots of back and forth. Anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you contact support, and say, “a note added November 8 is no longer in my account. It contained the phrase the brown fox jumps over the lazy dog, and it was added by my colleague, Colleen.” That’s a start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It leads support in a direction, and gets you help you faster. The more information that is shared benefits everyone. Win-win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever gone to the grocery store hungry without a list of what you want to buy?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t end well. You buy lots of stuff you don’t really need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same is true when you contact support without sharing specific information. It can cause more anxiety and waste valuable time for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ask-before-speaking-to-the-manager&quot;&gt;Ask before speaking to the manager&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May I speak with your manager?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s one the oldest customer tactics. And for good reason, it sadly, works a lot of the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve never thought much about this question until I was asked, &lt;em&gt;or not asked&lt;/em&gt;, it. It’s happened to me more than a few times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A customer emails your boss directly instead of interacting with you, or complains to your boss instead of asking you beforehand if there is anything else you can do to help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s demoralizing. It doesn’t matter what job you have, a feeling of autonomy and being empowered is so important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when a customer tries to go over top of a support person, it destroys those feelings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why I’ve learned to always ask if a manager or someone else could help me before going around the person who is trying to provide support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get that sometimes you have to do it. A support person does a bad job. I’ve certainly done a poor job in the past, and a customer went around me to try to get help from elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the time that isn’t a reflection of the person doing support though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s more of a reflection of the organization. If an organization doesn’t empower the people doing support, no one really wins. Especially, the customer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before trying to contact someone with a C-Level title, ask the person providing support first. This puts you in a better position to get help and the attention from their boss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tell-someone-when-they-do-a-good-job&quot;&gt;Tell someone when they do a good job&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitter and other social media platforms are full of complaints. Try a Twitter search for a common airline, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/search?f=tweets&amp;amp;vertical=default&amp;amp;q=%40United%20hate&amp;amp;src=typd&quot;&gt;like United&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you do a bad job, people will let you know. And they probably should. Word of mouth is powerful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actions speak louder than words. So if you constantly complain about a service or product, or shitty support, take your business elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As much as people call out poor support, you rarely see folks praising support when they do a good job. Most folks that are happy with a service or product, you don’t hear from. These satisfied folks tend to be more quiet. That’s completely fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would encourage you to tell a support person when they do a good job. Because it can make a support person’s day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve had really rough weeks where every customer interaction feels contentious, and then one customer tells me what a great job we’re doing and everything changes. It makes my day, and sometimes my week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same is true when I see a customer praise a teammate of mine. The good vibes bring a smile to my face, and make me proud to work with everyone. It can really lift the spirits of the people that do support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve learned you should never expect praise when working in support. So when someone does tell you that you do a good job, it makes it that much sweeter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can scream when someone does a bad job. And you can also pat someone on the back when they do a good job too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He’d say to me, ‘Shep, you know when I come into a restaurant, the chef looks to see when the plates come back if they’re empty,’” Gordon continued about Vergé.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s one of the world’s greatest chefs admitting the food is terrible, but eating every morsel of food on his plate and his friend’s plate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gordon explained further, “because he knew that if that plate came back empty, he made a &lt;strong&gt;happy man out of the chef&lt;/strong&gt;. If there was one piece of meat left on that plate, the chef might kill himself. He’s had Mr. Vergé at his restaurant and he didn’t eat everything? It had nothing to do with Vergé enjoying the food. It was him realizing what would make someone happy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vergé was a great chef. He was also a fine patron too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to remember, you too, can be a customer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thanks to this &lt;a href=&quot;http://chiseler.org/post/145157416821/life-after-supermensch-an-interview-with-shep&quot;&gt;Shep Gordon interview from The Chiseler&lt;/a&gt; for inspiration of this post. If you dig that interview, try watching the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dvd.netflix.com/Movie/Supermensch-The-Legend-of-Shep-Gordon/70292993&quot;&gt;documentary Supermensch&lt;/a&gt; on Shep Gordon or reading his book, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/They-Call-Supermensch-Backstage-Rock-2019n-2019Roll-ebook/dp/B00MMFN8QY&quot;&gt;They Call me Supermensch&lt;/a&gt;. Both include more fascinating stories about Vergé.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/customer-can-be-you/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/customer-can-be-you/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Curse of Knowledge</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Uh, it’s off Airport road. You should be able to get there from Umstead. I think or, or maybe go up to Estes?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I paused again. I was confusing the person asking me for directions more than I was confusing myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was a matter with me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I grew up in Chapel Hill and went to college there. I lived there for over a decade. I was a local.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when a stranger asked me for directions, I couldn’t tell them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stammered over and over, and told them they might need to ask someone else or look at their phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Was something wrong with me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most rewarding, and challenging, things about working at &lt;a href=&quot;https://highrisehq.com/&quot;&gt;Highrise&lt;/a&gt; is how fast the product changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our team runs on a &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://signalvnoise.com/posts/3811-stuck-again&quot;&gt;train schedule&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. This means every few weeks we announce an improvement or something new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It could be a big feature like &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/highrisehq/recurring-tasks-6f057cbe7561#.l90lx8dho&quot;&gt;recurring tasks&lt;/a&gt;, or something small like a &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/highrisehq/more-powerful-forwarding-33a95200bc67#.p9a0evkp7&quot;&gt;new rule for autoforwarding emails&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reward is we’re making the product more useful to ourselves because we use Highrise every day, and making it more handy to customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenge is documenting these changes. It’s informing people that use Highrise with what has changed, why it changed, and how to make use of the changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number one resource for this is our &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.highrisehq.com/broadcast/bulk-email/&quot;&gt;help site&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a living, breathing how-to guide or user manual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a beast of a resource to maintain. There are over 100 articles, countless screenshots, and videos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And with frequent updates, this snapshot or how-to guide of Highrise can go out of date fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It came to our team’s realization when updating a screenshot. The settings menu now has a new option for all users (&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/highrisehq/give-get-94bb3158541#.5kzoxolsy&quot;&gt;Referrals&lt;/a&gt;), and the old screenshot didn’t reflect that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a tiny change. A person new to Highrise might not even notice it. Our team did, so we updated the screenshot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This change sparked lots of others too. We began to notice videos were out of date by months. More screenshots too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A pull request with one commit, a change to a screenshot, turned into a two-week project. 277 changes later, our team updated the entire help site to more accurately reflect the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What took us so long to realize things were out of date?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nicholas Epley has a dynamite book on this topic. It’s called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Mindwise-Misunderstand-Others-Think-Believe/dp/1491544325&quot;&gt;Mindwise: Why We Misunderstand What Others Think, Believe, Feel, and Want&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the book, there is an eye-opening exercise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FINISHED FILES ARE THE RESULT OF YEARS OF SCIENTIFIC STUDY COMBINED WITH THE EXPERIENCE OF YEARS.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Epley asks you to count how many &lt;em&gt;fs&lt;/em&gt; are in this sentence. Start counting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How many &lt;em&gt;fs&lt;/em&gt; do you count?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it more than you can count on one hand?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If not, Epley has confirmed you’re a terrific reader, but a terrible counter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now count them again? Did you find &lt;strong&gt;all six &lt;em&gt;fs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t forget that the word &lt;em&gt;of&lt;/em&gt; has an &lt;em&gt;f&lt;/em&gt; in it. See all six now?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people, including myself, only &lt;strong&gt;found three &lt;em&gt;fs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Epley explains it has everything to do with knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He continues, “Your expertise of English blinds you from seeing some letters. You know how to read so well that you can hear the sounds of some letters as you read over them.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, because of your expertise, every time you see the word &lt;em&gt;of&lt;/em&gt;, you hear a &lt;em&gt;v&lt;/em&gt; rather than a &lt;em&gt;f&lt;/em&gt;, and you miss it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Epley points out, “First graders are more likely to find all six in this task than fifth graders, and young children are likely to do better than this than you did as well.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is known as the curse of knowledge. Why is knowledge a curse?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because once you have it, you can’t imagine what it’s not like to possess it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowledge or a level of expertise gives you the lens of a microscope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It means you notice subtle details a novice might not catch, and it also means your focus is so sharp, you might miss the big picture and you’ll struggle to understand a novice’s perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Epley offers a slew of &lt;a href=&quot;http://faculty.chicagobooth.edu/nicholas.epley/Mindwise/MindwiseTimesReview.pdf&quot;&gt;good examples&lt;/a&gt; in the book and elsewhere too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my favorites is how Clorox bought Hidden Valley Ranch Dressing and spent a decade trying to make the original recipe so that it did not need to be refrigerated. All of their internal taste tests of the dressing came back as worse than the original. Or so they thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hidden Valley finally sent a worse tasting version of the dressing to the market, and people loved it. Because not many people ever tasted the original dressing. The consumer’s perspective was way different than the company’s perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Epley writes further, “The expert’s problem is assuming that what’s so clear in his or her own mind is more obvious to others.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is something our own team fell into at Highrise. We were spotting tiny changes like typos or a missing menu option in a screenshot, but missing the bigger picture that almost everything was out of date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our perspective was way different than someone who started using the product yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it’s what happened to me when trying to give directions. I could probably get the stranger to the location if we rode in the same car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could tell her Airport Road is now named Martin Luther King Jr. Blvd. And there used to be tons of trees on Umstead Road that the city cutdown. I could point out all these tiny details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I couldn’t tell her how to get there on her own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was nothing wrong with me. I was cursed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cursed by knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-curse-of-knowledge/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-curse-of-knowledge/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Care Less</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Relationships are weird.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have names to describe all sorts of the relationships we have with other humans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friends. Acquaintances. A husband or wife. Brothers and sisters. Father. Son. Mother. Aunts and uncles. A cousin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So many names that indicate the context of a relationship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bosses and employees. Boardmembers. Colleagues or coworkers. Neighbors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Defendants and plaintiffs. A judge and jury.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Customers or clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all of these relationships, who is in control?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years, I’ve worked directly in customer support for companies that make software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a job I’ve come to really enjoy. It brings a lot of purpose to my work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People buy a product or subscribe by paying a monthly fee to use a product, and they have questions or requests. Someone needs help, and you help them. 
That’s my job. It’s to satisfy these questions and requests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s an incredible feeling when someone says something nice about you or the product. The folks that work in customer support know they get the glory first.  The &lt;a href=&quot;http://carokopp.com/post/39447960497/customer-service-secret&quot;&gt;warm fuzzies&lt;/a&gt;. The good vibes from the satisfied people that use the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But you can’t satisfy everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all the glory, there are people who only want to argue with you. The ones who say they have a question, but don’t ask one and end their email with &lt;em&gt;please advise&lt;/em&gt;. The people who aren’t a good fit for your product. And don’t know it yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Customer support can get ugly. When a customer says something not so kind, it can really take the wind out of your sails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve learned you shouldn’t take it personal. After all, they’re not blaming you, specifically. They’re blaming the product. You’re not the product. You’re you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that’s hard to do. Real damn hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years, I’ve found myself in a fair share of arguments or disagreements with customers. Situations where I get really worked up at times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So worked up I take it out on the people around me. Or so angry, I need to take a walk. Or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6sRQ9q4hzv4&amp;amp;list=PL_rR2s4GqBlZisb9D65sfOsd0ahQhBiWY&quot;&gt;play music like this&lt;/a&gt; with the volume turned all the way up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I feel like this, I realize it’s because I care. And it’s because I care a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I care about my job. And the people I work with. I care what people say about me and them. I care about the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I take pride in being able to help people. If someone is complaining, it’s my job to address it and listen. To try to understand why, so we can improve the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But when someone says something nasty or uncalled for, it’s hard not to take it personally. It’s so hard to &lt;a href=&quot;https://signalvnoise.com/posts/3124-give-it-five-minutes&quot;&gt;give it a good five minutes&lt;/a&gt;. To take some deep breaths before replying and do something silly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And because it’s hard, I’ve had my fair share of spirited back-and-forths with customers. Email conversations or threads that are exhausting. That are a road to nowhere and that leave me mentally spent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why do I do this to myself?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s because I &lt;strong&gt;care too much&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gordon Livingston was a therapist and author. He wrote lots of books on being human.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In one of his books, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Too-Soon-Old-Late-Smart/dp/1569243735&quot;&gt;Too Soon Old, Too Late Smart: Thirty True Things You Need to Know Now&lt;/a&gt;, he shares a lot of wisdom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each chapter is a truth that you need to know. And one chapter is on relationships. Livingston had lots of experiences with relationships, and cites helping couples navigate their marriages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s his truth about relationships:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Any relationship is under the control of the person who cares the least.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Livingston &lt;a href=&quot;http://people.hotdogsandeggs.com/gordon-livingston&quot;&gt;continues to explain&lt;/a&gt; that in these marriages, there is one person that cares a lot more than the other. The person who cares the most is at wits end about what to do. This person is pushing for the marriage counseling and they’re the one invested in the relationship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if the other person is not, the person who really cares feels powerless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This idea really hit me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It got me thinking about my own world. How I let myself I get so worked up when a customer says something unkind. And how I care too much, putting the other person in control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I care too much, I’m putting the other person in control of a relationship I shouldn’t even be in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have to have thick skin working in customer support. You have to let some things go. One person being upset isn’t a reflection of you or the majority of people that use the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It sounds backwards, but you’ve have to care less. Not more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This applies in every relationship in life too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A boss or colleague might not respect you. Or a neighbor or an acquaintance might be rude. You might disagree with others about politics, and others might say hurtful things to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you get worked up and care too much about what they say, you’re putting that person in control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s what they want too. The control. Don’t let them have it, they don’t deserve it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Care less.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/care-less/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/care-less/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Useful or Entertaining</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When you come up with a new idea, how do you know if it’s any &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good means different things to different people. A &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt; idea to one person might be a terrible idea to someone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of asking others if your idea is good or not, try asking yourself another question first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Internet is a curious and strange place. The last few months, I’ve noticed how Twitter has really changed. Twitter is losing the attention of a lot of people. Folks are giving that attention to other places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitter is &lt;a href=&quot;http://venturebeat.com/2015/03/18/twitter-will-die-if-it-doesnt-fix-its-noise-problem-says-early-investor-gary-vaynerchuk/&quot;&gt;noisy&lt;/a&gt;. There is a lot there that is expendable. Almost all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But for me, there are still a few folks worth following and listening to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are these people doing differently?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take Brad Panovich or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/wxbrad&quot;&gt;@wxbrad&lt;/a&gt;. He’s a meteorologist in Charlotte, NC. Panovich is probably my top recommendation to follow on Twitter. That is, of course, if you’re living in or around Charlotte.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He is relentless with information and forecasts. He works every day to share what to expect with the weather. Wondering if it’s going to rain on a summer day? &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/wxbrad/status/738127521284251648&quot;&gt;Check with Panovich&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He’s your personal weather expert. Twitter isn’t his only outlet. He shares on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/wxbradWCNC&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://wxbrad.com/&quot;&gt;his website/blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People trust Panovich. Why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because almost every single thing that he shares is useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/wxbrad&quot;&gt;@wxbrad&lt;/a&gt; TWC called for 80% all week for the weekend. We went with Brad, like always. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/oakisland?src=hash&quot;&gt;#oakisland&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/1rMVGigAZI&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/1rMVGigAZI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Joshua Helton (@j5hel) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/j5hel/status/737007560071491585&quot;&gt;May 29, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The weather can impact your day in a lot of different ways, and Panovich gets that. He strives to be reliable and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/wxbrad/status/737840000633581569&quot;&gt;accurate&lt;/a&gt;. He responds to folks that ask him questions, and that builds trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It makes Panovich useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another follow of mine that I enjoy is Spencer Hall or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/edsbs&quot;&gt;@edsbs&lt;/a&gt;. His tweets aren’t exactly useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take this one as an example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;north carolinaaaaaa&lt;br /&gt;come get your grades up&lt;br /&gt;take your shirt off &lt;br /&gt;twist it round your hand &lt;br /&gt;take a test without a proctor&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; SPENCER HALL (@edsbs) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/edsbs/status/524991281064607744&quot;&gt;October 22, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s not useful. And it’s not even funny to some people. To me? That’s hilarious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hall’s tweets sometimes make me audibly laugh, actually out loud, when in public. That’s incredible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hall has other outlets too. A blog, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.everydayshouldbesaturday.com/&quot;&gt;Every Day Should be Saturday&lt;/a&gt;. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/spencer-hall-8&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt;. He’s on snapchat (@edsbsnappy) and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/edsbs/&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt; too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Twitter, he has almost 100,000 followers. They’re not following him because he’s useful. You follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/edsbs/&quot;&gt;@edsbs&lt;/a&gt; because almost everything that he shares is entertaining.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/edsbs/status/735302406884360192&quot;&gt;pure entertainment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If someone comes to me with an a project or something that needs to be done, the first question I’ll ask is, “Is this useful? How is it useful?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And if it’s not useful, it better be entertaining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And if it’s not useful or entertaining, there is only one other basket left. That’s useless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To us, business is really not rocket science. It’s just do useful stuff. And avoid useless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Manoj Bhargava, founder of 5-Hour Energy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bhargava described how he runs his company and the question he asks when someone has an idea or project they want to work on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is this useful? If it’s not useful, is it entertaining?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 baskets. Useful and entertaining. If it doesn’t fall into one of those baskets, the idea is useless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stop wondering if your idea is any good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start asking yourself if your idea is useful or entertaining.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/useful-or-entertaining/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/useful-or-entertaining/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>If we had a Roadmap . . .</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://draftin.com:443/images/37798?token=uxgjD146EOJ9zWDnKtwev1sTDFMWBOaQyefOt-bneJEtF5h8ZSGyo7n08gZhtJhoDEZuSkxDRXqL03Shd-6PhUs&quot; alt=&quot;uber-ride-small.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some examples of emails we get about our product roadmap at &lt;a href=&quot;https://highrisehq.com/&quot;&gt;Highrise&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hope something like this is on the product roadmap.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Is such development planned in your roadmap soon?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’m following up to see if we can add this to the product roadmap.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You want the truth?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here it goes. Highrise doesn’t have a roadmap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our team doesn’t have a list of features with exact dates for release. We don’t know what’s going to be released on Tuesday, August 23.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can’t advise when something will be possible. We can’t confirm if something is on our roadmap. The product roadmap doesn’t exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don’t make promises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And really that’s all a roadmap is. A promise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A product roadmap is a promise that customers will get something on a specific date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s a real photo of a map at the top of this post. It was an Uber ride Jon and I took from a Boulder hotel in an attempt to get to the Denver Airport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://highrisehq.com/&quot;&gt;Highrise&lt;/a&gt; is a remote company. This means all of us work where we’re comfortable. We have team members in Chicago, Boulder, Minneapolis, and Charlotte. All over the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remote work is refreshing. It puts all the focus on getting work done. Our ancestors (aka Basecamp), &lt;a href=&quot;https://37signals.com/remote&quot;&gt;wrote a book on it&lt;/a&gt;. We believe in remote work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While remote work is great, every so often you need to meet your team face-to-face. There is no substitute for being able to look a colleague in the eye when you’re explaining or giving them a hug instead of saying thank you over chat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our team met in Boulder in the middle of March for a team retreat. Michael, who resides in Boulder, told us the weather would either be great or snow two feet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was lovely. We caught up and got to know one another better. We made progress on ways to improve Highrise and defined our priorities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The weather was perfect. We went on a hike together and enjoyed the outdoors. Had a lovely team dinner. The trip was going really well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then it changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of us were scheduled to leave on Wednesday, March 23.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up early and looked out the window of the hotel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holy shit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was about 4 or 5 inches of snow on the ground. And it was still snowing. Hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I looked at my phone. Blizzard warning for Denver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I checked my flights. Still on-time. Allegedly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next 8 hours of that day were something I’ll never forget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jon and I walked to a coffee shop in downtown Boulder and met another member of our team, Grant, to get some work done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were checking our flights every 15 minutes or so. Nathan and Lynette’s flight was already cancelled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somehow the flights Jon and I had were still on-time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We needed to get to the airport. And Jon scheduled a shuttle from the hotel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was time to go. The snow hadn’t stopped. It picked up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we got to the hotel to grab our bags, Jon got a phone call. It was the shuttle. They cancelled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a choice to make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try to take the public bus an hour from Boulder to Denver. Or call an Uber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We chose an Uber. I pulled up my phone and braced myself for what kind of car the driver was going to be in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chevrolet Suburban.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jon and I looked at each other. That might work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got in the Uber. Our driver, Marty, couldn’t have been nicer. He was a mountain man. Prepared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Alright, gentlemen. It says it should take about an hour and a half to get to the airport. There’s a few different ways we can go. If we get in trouble, I’ve got some blankets and Heath bars,” Marty said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marty’s pitch made us laugh. Blankets and Heath bars? We’re not going to get stranded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we started our route, the first highway we attempted to go on was closed. This was 10 minutes in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marty tried the next route. Gridlock. Bumper to bumper. The snow wasn’t stopping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marty said let’s turn around and try another route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jon got a notification on his phone. Flight cancelled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My flight was still on-time. Marty takes us to the next route. More traffic. We’re going at a snail’s pace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little over an hour has passed now. I check the Denver Airport’s Twitter account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Denver International Airport has made the decision to close the airport until further notice. Cont...&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Denver Int&amp;#39;l Airport (@DENAirport) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/DENAirport/status/712704864204275712&quot;&gt;March 23, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A minute later, my flight is cancelled. No surprise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, we’re in no man’s land between Boulder and Denver. We’re not leaving today and we’re not quite sure where we’re going either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marty suggests we try to get to a hotel that’s in the direction of the airport. Jon calls what feels like 20 hotels. Almost all are booked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jon lands a reservation for us at a hotel in Thornton, Colorado.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The destination is now a hotel in Thornton.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We stopped moving. Must be an accident ahead. Marty takes us on new route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re coming up on 2 hours in the car. I’m starting to think we might need that blanket and Heath bar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new route is a little more open. The Suburban is gaining some speed as we approach a hill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The car fishtails a little. And we’re stuck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marty asks if we can get out to push the car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might think team building happens with things like trust falls. Nope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try pushing a stranger’s car in driving snow with a co-worker. You’ll get to know each other. Fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jon and I get out and head to the back of the car. It’s a white-out. Snow is falling fast. And it’s wet. The snow on the ground is so packed it feels like cement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We push the car and nothing really is working. A few folks in passing cars stop and help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best advice they give us is the road ahead is closed. Turn around. Instead of pushing the car forward, we can go back now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marty maneuvers the Suburban and flips it around. We’re moving now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all take a deep breath. Share some four letter words. And agree let’s go back to Boulder if we can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marty drops us off back at the same place he picked us up. Almost 3 hours later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made it. My goodness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Can’t wait to tell y’all about the fun adventures and things we learned at our &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/highrise&quot;&gt;@highrise&lt;/a&gt; team get-together&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jon Phenow (@jphenow) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jphenow/status/712763468881862657&quot;&gt;March 23, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Jon and I got in that Uber, our flights were on time and we’re expecting to get to the airport in 90 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “roadmap” said we’d be getting home today. That was our expectation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that didn’t happen at all. It sucked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is &lt;em&gt;why our team doesn’t have a product roadmap&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our team doesn’t like making promises we can’t keep. We don’t like setting expectations and then letting people down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we did have a roadmap, I’d bet it would be full of detours. Much like our Uber ride. It would resemble a child’s first attempt at using an Etch a Sketch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lots of twists and turns. Backtracking. Turning around. A little messy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t to say we don’t have any clue what we’re working on. That’s far from the truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our team has &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.highrisehq.com/archive&quot;&gt;announced over 70 updates&lt;/a&gt; since taking over Highrise. Seventy. New features and improvements are announced almost every week. And that’s just what we choose to announce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can’t do that without some planning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our team has a general idea of what’s coming in the next month or so. After that, we gather the response of what we released and go from there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes this means we continue on with what we had planned. Other times it means we have to turn around. Scrap our plans and work to improve what was released in the last few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, when we released &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.highrisehq.com/post/134350595091/broadcast-send-bulk-email-with-highrise&quot;&gt;Broadcast&lt;/a&gt;, we started to notice a frequent feature request. Broadcast makes it possible to email multiple contacts at once. It replaces the need for an extra tool like MailChimp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we found people we’re having trouble selecting a group of contacts to email. Tags and filters were limiting, and it put pressure on our team to improve it. Fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This changed our priorities. We scrapped what was initially planned to improve tag filtering. We added &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.highrisehq.com/post/138550394736/company-tags-for-people-now-find-people-in&quot;&gt;company tags&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.highrisehq.com/post/139609834741/exclude-tags-not-tags&quot;&gt;NOT tags&lt;/a&gt; in our next releases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We changed our focus to help people use Broadcast. And that’s not something we anticipated until people starting using it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A roadmap wouldn’t have helped us there. It would of been pre-determined what we should be working on next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roadmaps are predictions and assumptions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But you can’t predict the future. Priorities change. Shit happens. And you have to adjust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just like Marty did when trying to get us to the Denver Airport. And the hotel in Thornton. And then back to Boulder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don’t have a product roadmap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if we did, it would have lots of detours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;P.S.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Wondering where our next detour is going to take us? Follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/highrise&quot;&gt;@highrise&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter, check out our recent announcements, or ask me &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cjgallo&quot;&gt;@cjgallo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/if-we-had-a-roadmap/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/if-we-had-a-roadmap/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Be the Plumber</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A 30-something immigrant with no fancy education or consumer product experience started a company in 2003. The product was first sales came out of the trunks of cars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9 years later, the company’s products were being snagged by people checking out at Walmart and sales exceeded $1 billion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How the hell did that happen?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the hardest parts about supporting customers is seeing things from their perspective. There were plenty of customers who knew the product better than me when I first started at Highrise 17 months ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s not a great feeling. Because people are asking you questions and you’re supposed to have answers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you get to know the product better?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my first 12 months at Highrise, our team tried using the product more and more. We assigned tasks for following up with customers. We tracked email with our dropbox addresses. We built support to autoforward in tons of mail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were learning the product, but we really weren’t using it as much as we could. Especially for supporting customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The majority of my time was spent in help desk software. That’s where I was replying to customers. It wasn’t spent in Highrise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day, our CEO, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/natekontny&quot;&gt;Nathan&lt;/a&gt;, asked me what would it take to use Highrise to support customers?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first reaction was that wouldn’t even work. There is no support queue. It would be terrible and slow us down a ton.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Nathan knew if we could pull it off, it would mean our entire team would spend a ton more time in Highrise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By using Highrise, it would become more useful to us and our customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it wasn’t going to be all ice cream and nuts. It was going to be tricky. Rough spots were ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our team started small. One of the first things we announced was &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.highrisehq.com/post/97143153266/highrise-announcements-gmail-forwards-sent&quot;&gt;autoforwarding support for Gmail&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All email was being autoforwarded into Highrise. It was a firehose of information. Overwhelming. Noisy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It became impossible to search and find information. It sucked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if our own team was having trouble with it, customers probably felt the same way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This shitty experience put pressure on us to make it better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little later our team built a way to &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.highrisehq.com/post/104175277771/mobile-access-connect-to-gmail-bulk-imports-and&quot;&gt;connect Gmail&lt;/a&gt; and send emails directly out of Highrise. Our support email address used Google Apps, so we were inching closer to being able to support customers with Highrise alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first version to send email out of Highrise was a bit underwhelming. You couldn’t attach files. No way to CC or BCC others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was good enough for us to start using it, but there was still too much friction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weeks later we &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.highrisehq.com/post/110643047531/gmail-highrise-just-got-a-lot-more-useful&quot;&gt;introduced rules&lt;/a&gt; including a way to only forward in email from existing contacts. This reduced the noise and made it easier for us to use Highrise.  The firehose was no longer always on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was still hard to find notes and emails when searching. Tons more email was still in our account. So we &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.highrisehq.com/post/129661506091/recency-search&quot;&gt;improved&lt;/a&gt; search and made it easier and faster to find things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When replying to customers, we sometimes needed to copy others or attach files when replying to customers. So our team made it possible to &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.highrisehq.com/post/129794050991/ccbcc-from-gmail-highrise&quot;&gt;CC/BCC from Highrise&lt;/a&gt; and followed that up with &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.highrisehq.com/post/131029305986/attachment-support-from-gmail-highrise&quot;&gt;attachment support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More progress. But still more pressure too. No queue for emails. We had no idea what needed to be replied to or what was outstanding or important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, we introduced a personal assistant. We call it &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.highrisehq.com/post/131497487921/good-morning-your-highrise-personal-assistant&quot;&gt;Good Morning&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good Morning helps us organize and respond to incoming activity that needs attention. It’s our take on a support queue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we were damn close.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We couldn’t tell who was replying to what. Our team sometimes replied to a customer twice because we had no idea someone else was already replying to them. Definitely not ideal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our team built &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.highrisehq.com/post/132608540101/good-morning-again&quot;&gt;presence&lt;/a&gt; to see if someone else is responding, and it improved. No more replying to the same customer twice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the fall of 2015, our team was using Highrise to reply to every customer email. Something I thought wouldn’t be possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5-Hour Energy founder Manoj Bhargava will tell you he grew his product company to over $1 billion in sales with combination of common sense and a sense of urgency. By not doing dumb stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bhargava claims his company isn’t efficient at all. They just don’t do useless stuff. He cut out everything that didn’t make money, didn’t improve the product, or didn’t make the customer happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Business isn’t complicated to Bhargava. It’s just do useful stuff. And avoid useless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That belief turned 5-Hour Energy into one of the most popular consumer products in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bhargava, who dropped out of Princeton after one year, doesn’t believe in MBAs. Why? They’re useless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It’s a simple thing. If you’re going to learn plumbing, go learn from a plumber that has actually seen a pipe. That has fixed a leak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Not just written about pipes, lectured on pipes, and researched pipes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’m not for theoretical plumbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Manoj Bhargava, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x46-XiMOoJE&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&amp;amp;t=25m5s&quot;&gt;Why a MBA is Useless&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our story is similar. Our team made a commitment to using Highrise more. Instead of being theoretical users of the product, we became customers of it. We depended on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We felt the pain our customers were telling us about. It wasn’t pleasant.  But it gave us a new insight into what it was like to use the product. 
It forced us to improve Highrise and to do it quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you have dig in and fix it from the inside. It might take a little pain, but it may also be the only way you’ll figure it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was inspired by this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x46-XiMOoJE&quot;&gt;talk&lt;/a&gt; from Manoj Bhargava.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/be-the-plumber/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/be-the-plumber/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Convenience</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“I can’t do this, no idea what this even means,” I confessed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Just read the instructions!” she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was staring at the sheet of paper with 24 small wooden pegs in hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Instructions!? There are no instructions! Only pictures. No words. I can’t read pictures,” I fired back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was already a long day. We drove hours to our new condo, and we’re ready to move in. The only task left was to put together furniture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IKEA furniture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dammit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why do people even buy this stuff?” I said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IKEA has been around for over half a century. There are over 300 stores in almost 50 countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why are they so successful?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clayton Christensen, author and Harvard Business professor, argues IKEA &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christenseninstitute.org/satisfying-the-patients-jobs-to-be-done/&quot;&gt;focuses on the job&lt;/a&gt; of the customer. The job is to furnish your place tomorrow because the next day you have to show up at work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s certainly one reasons why they’re successful. We bought a kitchen table, coffee table, and two chairs. It was put together in less than a day. With lots of curse words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kevin Maney might have a different take on why IKEA is successful. Maney &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Trade-Off-Some-Things-Catch-Others/dp/0385525958/?tag=mmr-support-20&quot;&gt;wrote a book&lt;/a&gt; on the trade-offs people make when buying products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His framework centers around two things. Fidelity and convenience. 
Fidelity being the total experience of something and convenience being how easy it is to get or do that experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, a high fidelity experience would seeing your favorite band live in concert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s probably going to cost you a good chunk of change to go to the concert. You’ve got to park, maybe take off work the next day or the day off to get there. It’s not really convenient at all. But it’s something you’ll likely remember for a long time, if not forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A convenient experience is Netflix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t have to go anywhere. You pay a cheap monthly fee, and can watch anything on any device. You can watch in bed if you want, and waste all kind of hours. Tons of content is available, and it’s not hard at all to get.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how does this relate to IKEA?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the surface, IKEA might not seem convenient at all. The closest IKEA to me is about 15 minutes. I live in uptown Charlotte, so extremely close to a big city. For a lot of others, IKEA is likely at least a 30 minute drive if not more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But when you get to an IKEA store, the convenience hits you right in the face. The entire store is built to get you to buy a ton of crap and get the hell out. If you’re hungry, they even have a restaurant. I’ve heard the Swedish meatballs aren’t that bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cost of IKEA furniture is reasonable. You’re going to save a lot more money than if you go to a high-end furniture store and have to worry about delivery and a salesman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most everything is in-stock. You don’t buy and have to schedule for a pick-up often, or at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can pick up everything you need at this giant store, and go home. One trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you get home, putting this stuff together is a pain in the ass. It takes some effort and time to do. But it can be done the same day, and your whole place is furnished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IKEA is convenient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been thinking about this a lot when working with customers every day at &lt;a href=&quot;https://highrisehq.com/&quot;&gt;Highrise&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ask myself, do we want to our support to be a high fidelity experience or a convenient one?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re a small team. We don’t have a phone number you can call. We don’t offer demos or in-person demos. We don’t have live chat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s all email. If you have a question, send us an email, and we reply back as fast as we can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This doesn’t jive with everyone. And I don’t expect it should.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One customer asked, “Why don’t you offer live chat? You should survey your customers.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fair question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the surface, live chat seems like a great channel to support folks. A convenient way to help customers while they’re in your product or service, or using your software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have 1 dedicated person working on support. At most, we’d have 2 people in the inbox at once. Maybe 3 in rare instances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Live chat is about immediacy. If we don’t reply to a customer’s live chat within 15 seconds, it’s a complete waste.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have thousands of customers. If 6 out of thousands write into live chat at the same time, that experience is going to be shitty for all of us. Not good for customers or our team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Others ask, “Why don’t you have a phone number?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same is true for phone support. With only 1 dedicated person, it’s hard to do. If more than 1 phone call comes in a time, customers have to wait. Or get put on hold. That stinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could outsource it? If we outsource phone support, we’re depriving our team and our customers from learning about why they’re even use our product. Pointless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we say we’re call customers back, with a team of only 1 or 2, we’re never going to be able to contact customers in a timely manner. Phone support is &lt;a href=&quot;http://wistia.com/blog/scaling-support-why-we-removed-our-phone-number-from-our-website&quot;&gt;tough to scale&lt;/a&gt; at a small size. It doesn’t mean we’ll never call customers. We can’t do it well right now though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why we only offer email support. It scales for our team, and we’ve built &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.highrisehq.com/email/good-morning/&quot;&gt;tools&lt;/a&gt; within our own product to do it better and faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/maxshelley/status/662639206095822848&quot;&gt;good at it&lt;/a&gt; too. It’s one of our strengths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On average, we can reply to people within minutes or the hour during normal business hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://help.highrisehq.com/&quot;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt; is our team’s best friend. And the customer’s too. If a customer can find an answer without contacting us at all, that saves everyone time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want our support to be convenient. If you have a question, you can help yourself. If not, send us an email, and we’ll reply back in 10 or 15 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our support could aim for a high fidelity experience. We could try live chat, add a phone number, travel to visit customers in person and give demos. But just because you can doesn’t mean you should.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All those fidelity things, we wouldn’t be any good at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Figure out what you should do and do it. Finally, decide what you should not do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Peter Drucker, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/The-Effective-Executive-Definitive-Harperbusiness/dp/0060833459&quot;&gt;The Effective Executive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We believe in investing in our strengths. Not our weaknesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Z1NpuKnuDyA&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&amp;amp;t=42m25s&quot;&gt;Good support&lt;/a&gt; gets you back to your work as fast as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s convenient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still can’t read those damn pictures. Give me words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do wish there was words in IKEA’s instruction booklets of how to put the furniture together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But know I now why there aren’t any. Take a look at their &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ikea.com/us/en/catalog/productsaz/0/&quot;&gt;list of products&lt;/a&gt;. So. Many. Products. Thousands of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s a lot of words. It wouldn’t be convenient to write and translate tons of words for over 12,000 different products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a trade-off. A compromise. IKEA focuses on what it does well. Its convenience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why I bought their stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/convenience/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/convenience/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How They Use It</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;How do people use Coca-Cola?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realize that this might be a wide-eyed question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They drink it, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People drink Coca-Cola.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, they do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.worldofcoca-cola.com/about-us/coca-cola-history/&quot;&gt;The estimated daily servings&lt;/a&gt; of Coca-Cola beverages is 1.9 billion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what if people use Coca-Cola in another way?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do people use your product? All in the same way?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marketing is exhausting right now. The people who describe what a product does rarely use the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People use acronyms and jargon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re a CRM. Full-service web solutions. It’s like Groupon for clergy members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re all guilty. I work with a small team on &lt;a href=&quot;https://highrisehq.com/&quot;&gt;Highrise&lt;/a&gt;. It can be described as a CRM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have no idea what CRM means. Oh, I know what it stands for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Customer relationship management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what does that mean?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If someone asks me how people use Highrise, I could say like a CRM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I try not to describe Highrise as a CRM. Because that’s not how all people use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our team tries to focus on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://justinjackson.ca/hidden/&quot;&gt;jobs people get done&lt;/a&gt; with Highrise. Why do they hire it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Highrise customers include real estate agents, nuns, and screenwriters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you think all these people use it in the same way?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I couldn’t understand what I was seeing. “Why the hell are they doing that?” I asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve never attended a NASCAR race, I recommend you do because it will change your perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might consider NASCAR to be a hilly-billy sport. Or maybe you don’t even consider a sport at all. I’m not here to debate that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NASCAR is a business, a multi-billion dollar one too. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.forbes.com/nascar-valuations/&quot;&gt;That’s a fact&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The access NASCAR gives fans is unreal. I had a chance to find this out myself a few years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a &lt;em&gt;Hot Pass&lt;/em&gt;, which means I was allowed to walk around when the garage was “hot” or cars were moving around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each car has its own team. The team consists of a driver, crew chief, jackman, gas man, tire changer, utility man, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lots are involved in making sure the car is working properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What can your team accomplish in 11 seconds?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s considered an above average pit stop for most NASCAR pit crews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, “Why they hell are they doing that again?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I asked as I saw the pit crew pouring out full two-liters of Coca-Cola on the asphalt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A friend replied, “Oh, that’s to keep the ground sticky for the pit crew. Can’t slip or it will cost you when making a pit stop.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pit crews look for any advantage they can get. 11 seconds is not a long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They’re resourceful. If they &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thenascarinsiders.com/2010/03/03/pit-stalls-a-sticky-situation/&quot;&gt;need more traction&lt;/a&gt;, they’ll figure out a way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I thought people only drink Coca-Cola?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve seen customers use Highrise to keep track of who they talk to, what they talk about, and when to follow-up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also seen folks use Highrise in a way that’s equivalent to pouring Coca-Cola on asphalt instead of drinking it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After conversing with customers every day, I’ve learned people use products how they want to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not how &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; want them too. How &lt;em&gt;they&lt;/em&gt; want to. It’s &lt;em&gt;their&lt;/em&gt; choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look around. Examples are all over the place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thekitchn.com/can-you-really-cook-salmon-in-a-dishwasher-putting-tips-to-the-test-in-the-kitchn-218048&quot;&gt;cook salmon with their dish washer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.snotr.com/video/8965/So_papa__how_do_you_like_the_iPad_we_got_you&quot;&gt;iPad as a cutting board&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pack &lt;a href=&quot;http://lifehacker.com/5874035/pack-shoes-in-hotel-shower-caps-to-keep-your-luggage-contents-clean&quot;&gt;shoes in a shower cap&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only pour Coca-Cola on the ground, but &lt;a href=&quot;http://prop-tricks.wonderhowto.com/how-to/clean-penny-with-coke-209448/&quot;&gt;use it to clean pennies&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no right or wrong way to use a product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because the person using the product decides how they use it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-they-use-it/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-they-use-it/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Workarounds</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You can’t do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why would you do that? That’s stupid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These were the thoughts running through my head as I was reading an email from a customer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I couldn’t believe what they were suggesting. It felt wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A huge lesson I am learning when interacting with customers every day is to be careful telling someone they can’t do something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine how it feels to be told you can’t do this or you can’t do that. It stinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, customers asked us, “How can I pin a note across the top of a contact’s page?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can’t do that. This is the response I tried on for awhile, and no one really got any satisfaction out of it. Me included.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day a customer took me to school with a clever hack. You &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; change the date a note is entered in &lt;a href=&quot;https://highrisehq.com/&quot;&gt;Highrise&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Say you have 3 notes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The first note is dated November 1, 2015.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The second note is dated October 29, 2015.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And the third note is dated October 11, 2015.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://draftin.com:443/images/34028?token=Y18V9RTl6aVrREocXSLyPxOTIIQUL4uc67IeKxVlS0VrqwUgrbdENO4qAjc1fy_GRrN4jen_Zjh3biLStGr8ZsU&quot; alt=&quot;notes-1.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The notes will appear in chronological order with the most recent note first. What if you want the third note to show first?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can’t do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, but you can. Edit the date of the first note. Change the year to 2016, and boom, the notes are ordered like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://draftin.com:443/images/34029?token=JPCHBif-1EvYPO5pKBhDuTljCQGJYJ4r7GwmKJmSePW5PNLBqKCPI-gOe7FJNzJl8QLJmc_n3ihbyIV1iLO0Mpk&quot; alt=&quot;notes-2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first reaction was that is wrong. And you shouldn’t do that. But after I acknowledged it is a clever trick, I became curious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why are you trying to pin notes?” I asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Because there is really important information we cannot miss about this contact and it is in this note. We missed it once because it was down the page, and it cost us,” the customer answered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wow. That makes total sense. And all it took was a question about what someone is trying to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adjusting the date to the time in the future became one of our team’s favorite customer hacks. It was an incredible workaround.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So incredible that our team took the time to make it possible to pin notes. Our CEO, Nathan, details &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.highrisehq.com/post/128642749811/pinning&quot;&gt;why we did it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is your product isn’t perfect. It has rough edges. It can’t do everything and anything. And it shouldn’t be able to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But even if certain things might seem impossible, don’t be so quick to believe they are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of telling someone they can’t do something, try explaining how it could be possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get into a conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ask questions. Try to understand what they are trying to do. Think. Find a hack that might help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where the magic happens. Where you learn why people are using your product and what they’re trying to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look for workarounds.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/workarounds/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/workarounds/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Opposite of Blame</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I requested an Uber and got much more than a ride home. I learned something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andy, my driver, was polite. We talked about his morning. How it was going. Small talk. The weather.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I asked, “How do you like working for Uber?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andy responded and spiraled into a rant about ratings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He mentions how he received a bad rating from a customer. But the rating wasn’t &lt;em&gt;his fault&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He dropped someone off, and they left trash directly behind his seat. Andy couldn’t see it, and when he picked up the next person, there was the trash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next customer saw the trash, got dropped off, and gave Andy a bad rating because his car was dirty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I got a bad rating, and didn’t even know why. It wasn’t &lt;strong&gt;my fault.&lt;/strong&gt; The last person who was in my car left a ton of trash behind my seat.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s tough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could relate to Andy. After spending the last few years in the support inbox, I’ve wrestled with blame every damn day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Customers blame you. And it’s not your fault they’re using Internet Explorer. Or they forgot their password. Or their credit card expired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can blame them. It’s easy. It takes no effort at all to place blame. None. All you need is a finger to point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But does that help?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Once you’re blaming, you can’t change. You’re just dependent on the other side. In fact, you’re their prisoner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;William Ury, &lt;a href=&quot;http://people.hotdogsandeggs.com/william-ury/&quot;&gt;a conversation with Simon Sinek&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blame is placing all the responsibility on someone else. It never helps. Not in any relationship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of putting the responsibility on someone else. Take it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t mean it’s your fault. It means you’re part of the problem. You could be a small part of it, but you’re in it. Accept that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because once you accept that you’re part of it, you can change it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can ask what version of Internet Explorer they’re using or if they can try another browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can send a password reset link or reset the password for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ask if they have a different credit card. Share steps to update their credit card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can take responsibility. Do it. Because it’s contagious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you take responsibility, people are more likely to work with you instead of blame you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The opposite of blame is taking responsibility.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blame/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blame/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Advice from the Future</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Over the last six months, I slogged through one of the largest projects of my career. Our team built the new &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.highrisehq.com/&quot;&gt;Highrise help site&lt;/a&gt;, a glorified, 105 article, user manual for &lt;a href=&quot;https://highrisehq.com/&quot;&gt;our product&lt;/a&gt;. We redesigned everything. Rewrote every article. Reorganized every topic and question. Below is the advice I wish I had before we got started.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear Chris,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m writing this advice from the future. Several support emails and text snippets from where you’re standing now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It might seem scary, but the next six months will be some of the toughest and most rewarding of your career. There is sure to be frustration and doubt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is some guidance to help you along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;start&quot;&gt;Start&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where do I start? If you find yourself asking this question over and over again, stop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just start. Anywhere. Cut it all in half.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t try to write a whole section in a day. Break it apart into smaller pieces. Try writing one article today. That’s it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you know it, you’ll build momentum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;everything-is-temporary&quot;&gt;Everything is Temporary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a matter of days, Highrise went from a product that hadn’t been updated in a long time to having its own dedicated development and support team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The product is changing fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A screenshot you take today will look different next week. It’s easy to balk and not start documenting the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can’t decide whether to start writing documentation because it will all change soon, stop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a breath. And make a decision. It’s not life or death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you make the wrong decision, fix it as fast as you can and move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything is temporary. Accept it and get going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;embrace-interruption&quot;&gt;Embrace Interruption&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You work in customer support. The nature of your job breeds interruption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A customer can email you at any time. You are managing multiple interactions at once. A team member can ask for help whenever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t fight it. You can’t win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make the time. Start to sacrifice and prioritize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schedule blocks of time to work on the help site. An hour on Monday. Two hours Friday afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t abandon your customers, but if replies are slower for a few hours, everyone will survive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interruptions happen. Schedule around them and make the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ask-for-help&quot;&gt;Ask for help&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You cannot do it all alone. Stop waiting to ask for help. You’re not perfect and you don’t have to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re surrounded by people that can help you. You’re lucky to be part of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://signalvnoise.com/posts/3837-combine&quot;&gt;team that is wicked smart and talented&lt;/a&gt;. They want to help you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ask them. Don’t feel guilty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The help site is the most important resource for your customers. Your team needs to have a say in it, and be able to pitch in. Their perspective is invaluable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You cannot do it all alone. Don’t try. Ask for help early and often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you ask for help, your team will introduce a concept to you. It’s DRY (don’t repeat yourself).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t write the same HTML to create anchor links over and over again. Automate it. Don’t know how to do it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ask for help. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MichaelDwan&quot;&gt;Michael&lt;/a&gt; can knock this out for you in minutes and he wants to help you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t write the same article twice. Yes, all the content you’re writing is interrelated. You still don’t have to repeat yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will write over 100 different articles. You can edit all of them on your own or check to make sure you’re not repeating yourself. But that’s tough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ask for help. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/heywren&quot;&gt;Wren&lt;/a&gt; knows her stuff. She can whip the content into shape and make sure you’re not repeating yourself. Wren can find gaps in the content and write new articles to help customers even more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you find yourself doing the same things over and over again, stop. Ask for help and see if you can eliminate some steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;play-the-long-game&quot;&gt;Play the Long Game&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project is not going to give you immediate results. Let go of expectations and the thirst for immediate satisfaction. It won’t happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anything worth doing takes time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will write for hours and feel like nothing has changed. You will believe you’re done with the project several times, only to remember something else. &lt;em&gt;You’re going to put all the videos in the wrong format and have to fix them.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where the real work happens. There are no shortcuts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You cannot estimate how long this project is going to take. Accept it will be done when it’s done. Don’t be afraid to launch, but realize it’s an investment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An investment that needs to be made long before you see any sign that is paying off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;keep-going&quot;&gt;Keep Going&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re going to feel relief when the help site launches. Good. Celebrate it and congratulate your team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But remember you’re not done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll never be done. The help site you built isn’t a filing cabinet that you’re opening for your customers. Don’t make them rummage around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make tweaks and pay attention to what your customers are looking for. Do everything you can to make it easy for people to find what they need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t stop there either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to create more videos. Take new screenshots. Write new articles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The help site is not a book that has been published. It’s a living, breathing resource that needs to be watered every single day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The help site is your best friend. Treat it that way. Take care of it and keep making it better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;one-more-thing&quot;&gt;One more thing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Share your experience with others. There are people going through the same thing as you that need to hear this. Pay it forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the best,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chris (from the future)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new help site launched July 6. It was built by the Highrise team using a combination of &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/docs/collections/&quot;&gt;Jekyll collections&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://swiftype.com/&quot;&gt;Swiftype&lt;/a&gt;, and elbow grease. Notice a typo, have a thought about the help site, or other questions?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Let me know. I’d love to hear it. I’m &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cjgallo&quot;&gt;@cjgallo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; on Twitter.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;PS - special thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/natekontny&quot;&gt;@natekontny&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://supportdriven.com/support-driven-chat/&quot;&gt;Support Driven&lt;/a&gt; community for help editing this post.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;TL;DR - check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://mygifs.withdraft.com/&quot;&gt;gif recap&lt;/a&gt; :)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/advice-from-the-future/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/advice-from-the-future/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Routine Puts You in Control</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You work from home? How great is that?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do you watch TV all day and wear pajamas?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not exactly. The part about the pajamas might be true sometimes. But it is the opposite of what a lot of people think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have worked remotely, or from home, for a little over a year now. The truth is you do not work less. You are tempted to work more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes a lot more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to commute to work every day. A 45 minute or hour long drive. I would get on the road around 6 AM and get home around 6:30 or 7 PM. That is a lot of time in the car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I worked in agencies where we had meetings that lasted so long there was a line to the bathroom when it was complete. A lot of time talking and not doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember being in open offices and getting interrupted by someone sneezing or getting up to get a drink. Someone is tapping you on the shoulder. You are never able to string together a quiet 20 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I work remotely, almost all of these things have vanished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have more time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, you might find yourself taking advantage of all this newfound time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might make dinner instead of getting take out. But soon you will find yourself working again after you eat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you blur the line between work and home, it is easy to work more. It can be dangerous. And lead to all sorts of burnout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you avoid it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The boring, methodical, and uninteresting things you do every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A routine is crucial to working at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Stress comes from a lack of control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Jeff Bezos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A routine is where you find control. Without one, you lose control. And on comes the stress of working more than you should.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does a routine look like?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is my routine this summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://draftin.com:443/images/30187?token=qqXlhUdYiD8UBydn6iGmF9XnKeRldGrUM_nJlHki29aj0z7ODEROtWHXuqTNKS986VJ06LUXuV8USxEuxa4HS78&quot; alt=&quot;routine.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few things to keep in mind about my routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It is Subject to Change&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My routine changes with the seasons. For example, I love waking up early, but when it is cold and dark in the winter, that is a bit tricky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My routine is not full proof. Things happen and come up. I cannot always follow it. But when I do, I feel in control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Email&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do not recommend everyone check email at the hours that I do. 
I work in customer support. Our company is never closed. People from around the world use our software 24 hours a day, seven days a week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We only provide email support. It is like a leaky faucet. Customers can always email you. Sometimes the faucet is on full blast. Other times it drips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do not have 24 hour coverage yet for our customers. This is the reason I check and answer emails for 30 minutes when I wake up and before I go to bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The emails will always be there. But if I can chip away at emails now, it is a reward for me when I am back online later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Balance and Variety&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A routine by definition does not involve much variety. But balance is key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The days are almost identical. In the mornings, I find a different form of exercise is important. Yoga and swimming are a good mix for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twice a week, I try to sleep in an hour longer. This is huge. It allows extra rest, but also feels like another reward for my body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little variety is good. Balance is better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is another quote that stuck with me from Jeff Bezos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you want to do more of something, make the friction less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you want to do less of something, make the friction more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bezos gives the example of putting the bag of potato chips on top the refrigerator, if you do not want to eat a lot of chips. This increases the friction and makes it harder for you to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same is true with your routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I am on my routine, in order to respond to a work email, I must be in the specific room where I keep my computer. It is a rule. I do not use my phone or another device to respond to work emails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means if I am in bed, and something pops up, I would have to get out of bed and travel to the room with my computer. I am increasing the friction, so I do not answer emails at all hours of the day. I am in control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, when I am off my routine, traveling or in a new location, stress arrives again. My computer is a step away in the same room with my bed. There is almost no friction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is easy to open the computer and respond to emails after hours. It is a tough habit to break. I am not in control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After working remotely for a year, I am not sure I could ever go back to working in an office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The amount of time you gain is priceless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am also not sure I could ever survive without a routine. It puts me in control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have your own routine? Any tips or tricks, let me know &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cjgallo&quot;&gt;@cjgallo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/routine/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/routine/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Just Tell Them</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Your product isn’t perfect. It has rough edges. Parts that take some time to understand. And things that aren’t easy on the first or second try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know where your customers might struggle. The tasks that take
more time than they should. The point where frustration sets in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You put together resources to help customers get acclimated to your product. Videos. Help articles. Text snippets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But do you tell your customers where they’re going to struggle? Or just make it seem like it’s not hard for anyone else?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took a while for this to sink in for me. I would send over links to outdated help articles. I would dance around the fact that certain things were going to be hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then I started trying another approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The big problem is not that the manual is hard (or bad). The problem is that we act as though it’s not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You can fix the problem immediately without fixing the manual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Just tell them.&lt;/em&gt;
Try it. It’s like a superpower. Not for you, for &lt;em&gt;them.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Kathy Sierra, &lt;a href=&quot;http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0636920036593.do&quot;&gt;Badass: Making Users Awesome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m honest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is going to involve more steps than you’d like, but we’re only an email away if you need more help.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You’re exactly right, it’s a pain. We don’t do a great job of handling this right now.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We know that’s not the answer you’d like, but hope it clarifies. And I’ve shared this example with our team as another vote for these upgrades.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it pays off. Because when you’re honest, people start to show confidence in you. &lt;em&gt;They begin to trust you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your customers don’t need you to be perfect. They need you to be honest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just tell them.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/just-tell-them/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/just-tell-them/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Multiple Choice</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Which part of this sentence is grammatically incorrect?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://draftin.com:443/images/26396?token=MG17dtfTJORKMOP4rnW-My9dVx1qyt1bThXViC6ilWY8kbUkMMwxZQnpMzQa2asNhLuqF_DZjTYBkH9gr3yezj0&quot; alt=&quot;spelling-grammar-sample-question.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A? B? C? D? Or E – no error at all?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine 50 identical questions like that. Each question with five choices. That’s 250 potential answers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Which of these words in spelled incorrectly?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A. committed
B. exhilarate 
C. jewelery
D. vacuum
E. None of the above&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now add another 50 questions just like that. Another 250 potential answers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;100 questions. All multiple choice. Five choices. 500 potential answers. 40 minutes. A score of 70 or better is a passing grade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Could you pass this test in 40 minutes?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I couldn’t for the longest time. And it was a requirement to get my undergraduate degree from the Journalism School at UNC-Chapel Hill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dreaded spelling and grammar test. Albeit, there’s likely a spelling or grammar error in this post, but my problem wasn’t exactly spelling or grammar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was multiple choices and the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first crack at the test? I answered 64 questions in 40 minutes. I couldn’t answer enough questions to earn a passing grade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I fell victim to anxiety. There were so many choices that I would analyze every choice. I found myself spending 5 or 10 minutes on one question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paralysis by analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A typical day in customer support involves different types of interactions. You’re presented with situations and have to determine the best way to help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, you could encounter the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I can’t log in. Please advise.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I keep getting this error, and don’t know what it means. Help me?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I lost my data. Help!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of these are missing information. The best answer to each of these interactions is a question. And it’s likely not just one question. It’s multiple questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you tried resetting your password? Can you check your spam folder to make sure the reset email didn’t end up there? Can you please take a screenshot of where you see this error? Can you please share an example of data that is missing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The questions give you a better idea of how to help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the tricky part about customer support is the faucet never turns off. It’s always running, meaning there is always someone that could be in need of your help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not all problems are created equal. A feature request doesn’t hold the same urgency as someone who cannot access their account. But everyone deserves to be helped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how can you help and manage all the requests that come in?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You ask questions. Lots of questions. But is it possible to ask too many questions at once?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think of the last time you became anxious. What created that feeling for you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bob Moesta explores the feeling of anxiety in his &lt;a href=&quot;http://shapeandsound.com/a-beginners-guide-to-the-jobs-to-be-done-framework/&quot;&gt;jobs-to-be-done&lt;/a&gt; framework. He examines why people choose to buy a certain product or service, and details this through a tool titled the Forces of Progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://justinjackson.ca/&quot;&gt;Justin Jackson&lt;/a&gt; created a &lt;a href=&quot;http://justinjackson.ca/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/jtbd-forces-diagram-1024x793.png&quot;&gt;handy diagram&lt;/a&gt; to illustrate the Forces of Progress. The gist is that making a decision is stressful. Because what if you make the wrong choice?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a conversation on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://5by5.tv/criticalpath/19&quot;&gt;Critical Path&lt;/a&gt; podcast, Moesta shares how every new idea brings anxiety. He gives the example of a family that is moving and needs to choose between different moving companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moesta is part of a home building company that sets to understand their customers. He describes all that goes into a decision of choosing a moving company. And how he and his home building company helped these people make choices by eliminating anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an excerpt of &lt;a href=&quot;http://people.hotdogsandeggs.com/2014/09/16/bob-moesta/&quot;&gt;the conversation&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Because all of a sudden it’s like will they be gentle? Are they insured? If they break something, what will happen?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;So there’s all those kind of things that you need to make sure you understand, even though choice is important. Too much choice is actually paralyzing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;On the home building side, we’d sometimes have to make a thousand decisions about cabinets and flooring and carpeting. And simplifying that and saying there are three packages and this is where they fit. Just pick the color and we’ll do everything else for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Over-choice actually creates more anxiety and non-consumption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Bob Moesta, &lt;a href=&quot;http://people.hotdogsandeggs.com/2014/09/16/bob-moesta/&quot;&gt;Jobs-to-be-done&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Too many choices can do more harm than good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A great example of this is choosing what to order from different restaurants. Let’s compare the two menus of Cheesecake Factory and In-N-Out Burger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s over &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecheesecakefactory.com/menu/&quot;&gt;10 categories&lt;/a&gt; on the Cheesecake Factory menu. 10! You can order pizza, spicy cashew chicken, a rib-eye-steak, or shrimp and chicken gumbo from the same place. That’s a lot of choices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In-N-Out Burger’s menu is simple. Burgers, fries, and shakes. There’s more options on their secret menu. But it’s a not a hard choice to make. You know what you’re getting when you go to In-N-Out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is clear in your product. A great user experience often involves very little choice. Like an In-N-Out Burger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If anything and everything is possible in your product, it will probably create lots of anxiety. See Cheesecake Factory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But is the same true in how you interact with customers?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a customer wrote in that data was missing from their account, I responded over email quickly and asked several questions. 5 total.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you have an example of what is missing? Are you using any 3rd party integrations? When did you notice this was missing? Have you checked the trash in your account? Are other members of your account seeing the data missing too?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holy questions batman. I just gave a customer a multiple choice test and created lots of anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If something is missing, you’re already in a state of anxiety. There’s no need to increase that anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am guilty of asking too many questions without remembering it’s a conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your friend walked up to you and said I lost my keys, you wouldn’t ask five questions without getting an answer first. You ask a question and get a reply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same is true when working with customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find the most important question to ask and start there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;D.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s the correct answer to the question at the beginning of this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A secret behind the spelling and grammar test is you could take it an unlimited amount of times before earning a passing grade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I took the test over 20 times. It took a while to curb my anxiety, but my grade was a 92 the last time I took it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few years after I graduated, the UNC School of Journalism and Mass Communication &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jomc.unc.edu/spellinggrammar&quot;&gt;changed&lt;/a&gt; the spelling and grammar test. The format was adjusted and an additional 10 minutes was added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because too many choices can cause more harm than good.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/multiple-choice/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/multiple-choice/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Procrastination</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We all procrastinate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether it’s watching another episode of Veronica Mars instead of cleaning the kitchen, or scrolling through Twitter instead of responding to that email, or grabbing lunch with a friend instead of working out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Procrastination is something we all do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://danariely.com/&quot;&gt;Dan Ariely&lt;/a&gt;, a professor of psychology and behavioral economics, describes procrastination as a dilemma. This dilemma is between what is good for us now and what is good for us in the long term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ariely authored &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/The-Irrational-Bundle-Predictably-Irrationality-ebook/dp/B00BHEJ4IW&quot;&gt;three fascinating books&lt;/a&gt;, exploring the intersection of  psychology and economics, and how humans are predictably irrational.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The experiments featured in his books include serving beer with vinegar, giving away free Hershey’s Kiss, and allowing college students to choose deadlines or no deadlines when submitting final papers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I found myself re-reading through his books, one point jumped out at me and hit me right between the eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Giving up on our long-term goals for immediate gratification, my friends, is procrastination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Dan Ariely, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Predictably-Irrational-Revised-Expanded-Edition/dp/0061353248&quot;&gt;Predictably Irrational&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re working with customers every day, you experience some highs and lows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, you might be the person that takes the brunt of complaints or be berated by someone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But more often than not, you’re the first one to receive praise and thanks from others too. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/carokopp&quot;&gt;Carolyn Kopprasch&lt;/a&gt; explains these are the &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.bufferapp.com/customer-service-success-stories/&quot;&gt;Warm Fuzzies&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I’ve found at &lt;a href=&quot;https://highrisehq.com/&quot;&gt;Highrise&lt;/a&gt;, there are ways to earn the Warm Fuzzies and avoid the rants or complaints.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve learned doing the work for the customer and saving them time brings lots of Warm Fuzzies. Or commenting on their business or website is good for a thank you too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another tough lesson is that you can’t always get the Warm Fuzzies. Sometimes you have to disappoint people that are using your product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Highrise hasn’t been updated for a very long time. We’re fortunate to have an awesome group of customers, but all of us have gotten very used to how Highrise works. Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://signalvnoise.com/posts/3837-combine&quot;&gt;small team&lt;/a&gt; of five people is tasked with making the product better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenge is there are lots of ways to make it better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve scrolled through past customer history and found customers demanding for identical feature requests in 2010 as they do today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our iPhone app is outdated. It looks sharp on an iPhone 4, but customers ask us almost daily when the new app will be completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Android app? Highrise has never built their own native Android app. But some customers think without one, Highrise is useless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After an interaction with one customer, it became clear to me that there are just some people you have to disappoint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few feature request emails back and forth, me explaining how we’re going to consider ways to make this easier in the future, the customer’s patience evaporated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I see you making changes, but none help me. This can’t be that hard. Just fix it. It’s probably one-day total of development time.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This all brought me back to procrastination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of the practical advice about procrastination is about ways to overcome it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;13 tips to help you stop procrastinating. Yes, I find it ironic that’s a BuzzFeed headline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We associate procrastination with being bad. It’s something we need to beat or overcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But is it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/paulg&quot;&gt;Paul Graham&lt;/a&gt; makes a case for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.paulgraham.com/procrastination.html&quot;&gt;good and bad procrastination&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Ariely teaches us, procrastination is a dilemma. Graham details the three types of procrastination, explaining instead of working on something you either:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;do nothing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;do something less important&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;do something more important&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first option is what we all think of procrastination, doing nothing at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Graham argues the third option is good procrastination. And the most dangerous type of procrastination, or the bad, is the second option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re spending time doing something less important, it means you’re not spending time doing something more important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can rearrange your whole inbox and label specific messages. And you would probably feel like you got something done, but you didn’t reply to a single email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bad procrastination shakes the hand and plays nice with easy problems. The cross-it-off your to-do list problems. The type of problems that bring immediate gratification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choosing to do something more important is hard. Good procrastination wrestles with the big, hairy problems that take time. The type of problems you invest in today, and don’t see the reward for another six or seven months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The customer is probably right. It might only be one day of development time to fix her problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it’s not that easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As one of my fellow team members explained, “time spent fixing things is time spent not building new things, and the future of the company depends on us building new things.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Procrastination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I was writing my reply to the customer, I found myself with two choices. A dilemma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I could explain to my team that we need to fix this for her, and we could fix it. Warm Fuzzies for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I could disappoint her and explain that our time is not best spent fixing this problem right now. Disappointment.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both choices involve procrastination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first choice is the bad type of procrastination. It’s doing something less important. It’s giving up our long-term goal for a reward - the Warm Fuzzies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second choice is good procrastination. It’s working on something more important. It’s committing to our long-term goal and deferring the reward for another day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a dilemma we all face every day. You can choose the immediate gratification or the long-term goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re going to procrastinate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you choose do something less important and other times you choose do something more important. And sometimes, you choose to do nothing at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What will you choose today?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/procrastination/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/procrastination/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Support Your Product Like a Customer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The housekeeper asks for confirmation, “you promise you won’t tell my boss?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I will not tell your boss,” the occupational psychologist nods in agreement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/+JonathanKorman/posts&quot;&gt;Jonathan Korman&lt;/a&gt; shares a &lt;a href=&quot;http://miniver.blogspot.com/2014/10/policy-violations.html&quot;&gt;story&lt;/a&gt; about policy violations. Korman details the dialogue between an occupational psychologist and a hotel housekeeper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you think is the last thing a hotel housekeeper does before leaving a cleaned room?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The housekeeper admits, “the last thing I do is lie on the bed.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hotel obviously does not want housekeepers to lie on the bed before a customer enters the room. There’s even a policy against it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why would the housekeeper do it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last month, I’ve been training with a new support team. This means learning a new product and getting acclimated to a new group of customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://highrisehq.com&quot;&gt;Highrise&lt;/a&gt; has been a successful product for almost a decade. Built by &lt;a href=&quot;http://basecamp.com&quot;&gt;Basecamp&lt;/a&gt; (formerly 37signals), the product is used by thousands and thousands of people. And it’s in the midst of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://signalvnoise.com/posts/3770-big-news-for-highrise&quot;&gt;transition&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new CEO, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/natekonty&quot;&gt;Nathan Kontny&lt;/a&gt;, took over in August. Nate is responsible for assembling a new team and bringing momentum to a product thirsty for love and attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After speaking with Nate about joining to support customers, his advice was simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sign-up for an account and start using the product. Use it to keep in touch with friends or to remind you when your next dentist appointment is scheduled. Just start using it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I did. I used Highrise to organize a emails between Alyssa and Ian about writing for the Snappy blog. And I used it to remind me to send a congratulatory email to my friend who just announced he and his wife were having a child.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started to see how Highrise could help me. And I became a customer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steve Wozniak and Steve Jobs built the first Apple computer. They could of went out and bought an IBM computer instead. But they didn’t it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jobs explains why in his &lt;a href=&quot;http://people.hotdogsandeggs.com/2014/01/21/steve-jobs/&quot;&gt;1997 Apple Worldwide Developers Conference&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Every good product I’ve seen in this industry is because a group of people cared deeply about making something wonderful that they and their friends wanted. You know? They wanted to use it themselves. That’s how the Apple I came about, the Apple II, the Macintosh - that’s how everything I know that’s good has come about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If Woz and I could of went down and plunked $2,000 bucks and bought an Apple II, why would we have built one? We weren’t trying to start a company, we were trying to get a computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Steve Jobs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wozniak and Jobs were the first customers of Apple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot of advice about how to train new employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might recommend that they review policies and procedures to learn how the team gets things done. Or you might suggest a new employee read a book related to the industry.  Maybe there is a training program that all new team members go through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the challenges of training for me was working remotely. I haven’t had a chance to shake hands with the new Highrise team or Basecamp crew. It meant over-communication was not a choice, but a necessity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when it came down to training, there was one common thread amongst all the advice I received from the stellar Basecamp support team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Basecamp team would send me customer questions and leave me hints on how to respond. Next, I would draft a response and send it back to the team member before replying to the customer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hints directed me to a help article or suggested a text snippet that saved me some time. But above all, the main piece of advice was simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why don’t you give this a try using your own Highrise account?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could review help docs, watch videos, ask a million questions to other team members, and it would help me learn over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or I could use the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I started using Highrise more and more. And I was able to see and feel its rough edges. I put myself in similar situations that a customer would find themselves in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt what is was like to not be able to set a recurring task. Or to try and map custom fields when importing of contacts. And to search for duplicates in my account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I became a customer, and it’s helping me so much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s still a lot of customers out there that know Highrise better than I do. After all, there is no substitute for experience. Some customers have been using it for years. I’m just a few months in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that’s ok. Because I know by using the product, I’ll learn what it feels like to be a customer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t think of any better advice for a new employee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If I don’t, I cannot be sure that the room is clean,” the housekeeper confessed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Korman continued to describe, the housekeeper knew by laying on the bed there are things you see from that position you can’t see from anywhere else. It’s usually one of the first things a customer will do upon entering a hotel room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The housekeeper was able to see things from the customer’s perspective by lying on the bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She could feel what it was like to be a customer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Special thanks to the Basecamp support team, the new Highrise team, and Jonathan Korman for sharing &lt;a href=&quot;http://miniver.blogspot.com/2014/10/policy-violations.html&quot;&gt;this blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/support-like-a-customer/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/support-like-a-customer/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thanks for Understanding</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Two stories to share. Compare and contrast. Both involve trips to a cafe. And how these places communicate with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;first-story-were-not-open-yet&quot;&gt;First Story: We’re Not Open Yet&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s 8:56 a.m. on a Saturday morning. Outside of South Block Cafe, a man is clearing tables and setting up chairs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The door to the cafe is propped open. There’s no sign on the door. No “open” or “closed” cues for people passing by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My girlfriend and I decided to go inside. We inched inside, not knowing if we were allowed in or not. Ah, screw it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t our first time inside the cafe. We’ve been there a few times before. We thought they might even recognize us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Not open yet! We’re not open yet!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As if we walked in on a teenager with a “do not disturb” sign hanging from his door, the employees yelled at us that they we’re not open. It’s 8:58 a.m. In two minutes, they’ll open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We backtracked out of the cafe. “That was really rude,” we both said to each other. And we left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went to another coffee shop a block up the rode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;second-story-give-me-the-green-light&quot;&gt;Second Story: Give me the Green Light&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About a week later, we grabbed some coffee and brunch with friends in Georgetown. We hit this spot called &lt;a href=&quot;http://bakedandwired.com/&quot;&gt;Baked and Wired&lt;/a&gt;. You should check it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We strolled in and noticed a long line of people waiting for their drinks. As we stood there, a person from behind the counter walked up to us and asked what we wanted to drink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They wrote out names on the coffee cup in their hands. And then instructed us where we could pay for our drinks or choose a quiche or muffin to eat. After you pay for you meal, you join everyone else and wait for your drink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there is a message to set your expectation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://draftin.com:443/images/21700?token=s6GLYwiNgWjydCnSv6RQrPTnO3r1inM6lw96cX76JApuwcAAmP1vFjBuk_gJQbBQfgWRxoWgljMmhH2MTcvqvYA&quot; alt=&quot;baked-and-wired-understanding.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These simple sentences let you know to hang tight. It’s a clear message. And it reads to you as if a human is on the other end writing it. Because they are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After my name was called, I grabbed my delicious drink and we snagged a table to sit down. The table was positioned in the back on the cafe. And in the corner there was a door with a green light illuminated over it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People we’re walking back towards the door. And then turning right back around. Others would walk up, and then read the sign on the door, and wait outside. Some would read the sign and just walk back to their tables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the bathroom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve all had the experience of finally locating the bathroom in a cafe. But the door is closed and we’re guessing if someone is actually inside. You try to knock or open the door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might have walked in on someone before. That’s embarrassing for everyone. You might knock, not hear anything, and then try to turn the door knob, only to be shut out. It sucks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://draftin.com:443/images/21701?token=XnXzrKXmfn17_u-GPSiCjiE_ckfuTKWrO_fAiTAg3qwIbEWpuivdUrJ-50pp-Fjg3FlYVjRJX8JLTBUCifEGe5A&quot; alt=&quot;baked-and-wired-bathroom.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why Baked and Wired put a green light above the door. On the door reads a simple message too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This is a bathroom. When the light above is green, someone is probably in there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These little messages are sprinkled through the entire cafe. They make you feel welcomed and happy to be there. It’s like your little tour guide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You run into instructions every day. It could be to “Walk” or “Don’t Walk” across the street. Or to “sign out” of your favorite app. Maybe it’s to “unsubscribe” from an email list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instructions. These messages can make it easy for you or impossible. The words can make you feel at ease or angry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nicole Fenton, the co-author of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nicelysaid.co/&quot;&gt;Nicely Said&lt;/a&gt;, shares her goals for these messages. In her blog post, &lt;a href=&quot;http://nicolefenton.com/interface-writing/&quot;&gt;Interface Writing&lt;/a&gt;, she gives countless examples of how to get your point across and show you care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Be clear.
Be kind.
Be careful.
Be honest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Nicole Fenton, &lt;a href=&quot;http://nicolefenton.com/interface-writing/&quot;&gt;Interface Writing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first glance, the difference in these messages might not seem all that important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;South Block Cafe left us wondering if they we’re open and they told us to get out. Not in those words. But that’s how we felt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Baked and Wired made it clear what to expect. It made us smile. And really enjoy our time there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guess which one we haven’t been back to yet?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;South Block Cafe. Thanks for understanding.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/thanks-for-understanding/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/thanks-for-understanding/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Other People's Shoes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Straight to voice mail…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10 minutes have passed. “Should I call again?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Karl is a busy man. He’s an entrepreneur. Karl founded his company two years ago and it’s finally turning a profit. He’s responsible for more than 20 employees and hundreds of customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At home, Karl and his wife have two sons. A four-year-old and a two-year-old. At the moment, his wife is pregnant again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Karl is late for our scheduled phone call. We’ve already rescheduled twice. And he’s now 20 minutes late. So I call again. Karl picks up, “Sorry, Chris. My son is sick, the other one won’t leave his mom alone. And I’m working from home today. It’s a full-time job taking care of these guys.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I could imagine. Do you want to reschedule?” I responded without even recognizing the mistake I just made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Karl responded with a simple question, “Oh, do you have kids too?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ve heard the old adage. Put yourself in the other person’s shoes. It’s all about seeing things from their perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your mother, father, teacher, or mentor has probably mentioned it to you before. Therefore, this is something most of us know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it’s not that simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You don’t know how it feels to be me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Tom Petty, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ygfA1A45tn8&quot;&gt;You Don’t Know How it Feels&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tom Petty speaks the truth here. The idea of putting yourself in someone else’s shoes is not a lesson in sympathy. It’s about empathy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difference between empathy and sympathy is only two letters. Don’t mistake one for the other. They’re different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, sympathy is saying sorry to a friend who lost her job. Sympathy is sending a card to a friend after they’ve lost a loved one. Sympathy is donating your time and money to help disaster relief victims.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Empathy is having been fired from a job, knowing how it feels, and identifying with someone who experienced the same thing. Empathy is losing a loved one, feeling the pain of that loss and being able to identify with someone in the same situation. Empathy is losing your house to a disaster and connecting with a person who went through the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sympathy is showing pity or compassion for someone else. Empathy is connecting with someone who went through a similar disappointment or loss as you. It’s identifying with that same feeling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a younger brother, I grew up following my big brother to all his soccer games. He played all around the country. Florida. DC. Indiana. His travel team was good and so was he. They won lots of games but lost their fair share of them too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll never forget his reaction after one of their major losses. He is ultra-competitive. I mean he doesn’t even let me win a game of tic-tack-toe. If I beat him, he would be furious for days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The soccer moms (and parents) would support the players at each game. When the team lost, the parents would be sympathetic. After a losing this game, they stopped the kids while they were walking off the field to say, “It’s okay. It’s okay. Get them next time.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My brother heard this and his eyes rolled. He was a teenager at the time, and you’ll never imagine the words that came out of his mouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“No. It’s not f*cking okay.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was right. They lost and it sucked. It was far from okay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was disappointing, devastating, and frustrating to lose a game. All the players knew that. They knew what it felt like to play in that game and not win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The parents didn’t know. They weren’t the ones practicing and playing in the games. They could offer compassion, but they didn’t know how it felt to be one of the team players. The parents were providing sympathy, not empathy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Empathy is a major ingredient of interacting with other people. It’s just often confused with sympathy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We think by saying, “Put yourself in the other person’s shoes,” we will magically empathize with them. It’s simply not true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This lesson was a tough one for me to learn. As I’ve grown to working in customer support, I know empathy is a big part of the job. It’s how you connect with your customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can all be empathetic, right? Just put their shoes on. But that morning when Karl asked me that question, I realized I had it all wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh, do you have kids too?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh, no I don’t. I’ve got a long way to go before that.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Karl acknowledged what I said. And then paused and told me, “Then you really can’t imagine how it is. Because you don’t have kids yet.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went on to have a great conversation, but I was humbled. Karl was exactly right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have no idea how it feels to have kids. I struggle enough getting myself out of bed and making my lunch every day. I can’t even imagine having two kids under five with another on the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could sympathize with Karl. But I couldn’t empathize with him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not even if I put on his shoes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/other-people-shoes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/other-people-shoes/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Small Human Touches</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Does anyone like waiting in line?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is someone in front you and someone behind you. You’re stuck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember standing in line at Time Warner Cable one Saturday morning to return equipment. I was there for an hour and a half with other brave souls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ninety-two. Time Warner Cable literally passed out numbers. That’s a terrible way to make people feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of us often forget to be human today. We’re on our gadgets all day. We interact with screens more than we do with other people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few days ago I went to search for a flight. There’s tons of choices to book travel. I settled on an app my brother told me to check out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hipmunk.com/&quot;&gt;Hipmunk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why did he tell me about Hipmunk?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Compare flights, cheap prices with easy connections too. And they have this funny looking mascot.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A mascot? What does that have to do with me finding a flight?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever you search for a flight, you’ll land on a loading screen as Hipmunk is pulling all the data from different airlines together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s like you’re in line waiting your turn to see available flights. Hipmunk could present a simple progress bar that alerts you to be patient. But that would make you feel kind of like a number. It’s boring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead here’s the screen you see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://draftin.com:443/images/21124?token=9Q_uElI5D8R9lW4Sd7qmltBSerG0d3o7isFYAquJbq7jIRMthuSJnLVsxezidxxZzt8kmgLwMOrz8G3gkJEPqAs&quot; alt=&quot;hipmunk-mascot.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That makes me smile. Every single time. It never fails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same is true for their mobile app. Here’s the screen you see on your mobile device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://draftin.com:443/images/21126?token=f_IFLKylXo6ndrwY-Fryjz8F2Vt0I4BU5N3ZAqGbdYJ58pRWwAAVlRbj2D_nektIi-qAVV8Q6i3CVTGm3wNXt20&quot; alt=&quot;hipmunk-mobile-mascot.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same mascot plus a proverb from Tzu. There’s no boring progress bar that’s like watching grass grow or paint dry. This mascot makes you feel human.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;People are interacting with our products in most cases with a computer or some handheld device that isn’t very human at all. Like it’s a robot at the end of the day. And any opportunity to remind them that they’re are human beings working on this thing to make this kind of human connection is one that you have to seize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bloomberg.com/video/93287115-the-secret-to-tech-startup-mascots-a-great-product.html/&quot;&gt;Alexis Ohanian, co-founder of Hipmunk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re not a number. Or a robot. You’re a person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look for opportunities to remind yourself and others around you that we’re all just human beings.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/small-human-touches/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/small-human-touches/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>No Longer Mandatory</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Home run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was his professional at-bat. And he catapulted the ball over the fence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His name was Tim Wakefield. A lanky first baseman for the Single A Watertown Pirates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wakefield had a bad habit. He liked throwing a knuckleball around the infield during practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He threw it so much, the manager, Stan Clinburn had to urge him to stop and throw the ball straight. Wakefield didn’t listen. It wasn’t mandatory that he throw the ball a certain way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was slotted to be a home-run hitting first baseman. Why throw a knuckleball? It was a circus pitch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But his swing had a few holes in it too. Wakefield struck out 92 times in 256 at-bats in his first two seasons. And that was in Single A.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How could a player who struck out 36 percent of the time make it major leagues?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Everyone knows as soon as you make something mandatory, it becomes the opposite of what you want to do for a living.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://people.hotdogsandeggs.com/2014/02/01/jessica-hische/&quot;&gt;Jessica Hische, Learn the Tools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People do not like to be told what to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first job was a sports information director at my alma mater. It’s a fancy way of saying I was the middle man between athletes, coaches, and the media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of our tasks was transcribing quotes of coaches and athletes. This way we did the media a favor. Reporters could easily pull a quote for their story or deadline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I grew to hate it. Because it was a mandatory part of my job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Six months ago, I found myself watching a long interview with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jasonfried&quot;&gt;Jason Fried&lt;/a&gt;. The Chicago Founders’ Stories series, hosted by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/PatRyanChicago&quot;&gt;Pat Ryan&lt;/a&gt;, asked Jason &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/88749951&quot;&gt;questions&lt;/a&gt; about Basecamp, his company. It was a fascinating interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So much that I found myself playing a few parts back. One specific part where Jason discusses the advice they received from Jeff Bezos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few minutes later, I started &lt;a href=&quot;http://people.hotdogsandeggs.com/2014/02/21/jason-fried/&quot;&gt;transcribing&lt;/a&gt; what he was saying. This was a task I used to hate. But here I was transcribing an interview in my free time just because I could.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was no longer mandatory. I found myself wanting to transcribe other talks like this &lt;a href=&quot;http://people.hotdogsandeggs.com/2014/01/21/steve-jobs/&quot;&gt;1997 Q&amp;amp;A with Steve Jobs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I transcribe about an interview a week. It started as me &lt;a href=&quot;http://talks.withdraft.com&quot;&gt;hosting them&lt;/a&gt; with my favorite web app &lt;a href=&quot;http://draftin.com&quot;&gt;Draft&lt;/a&gt;. And now it’s morphed into a side project on my personal site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve done 23 total and you can check out the full list at &lt;a href=&quot;http://people.hotdogsandeggs.com/list/&quot;&gt;people.hotdogsandeggs.com/list&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://draftin.com:443/images/20578?token=hFF1OUGZkqB7VniwEUC9YlyjK7KTuMdZRYQh66gRRbDGJ3MnzO1xnjXuaqieMjqNvVuZ7aQs09ZXZq5UbAFL24E&quot; alt=&quot;abranch.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m getting a lot out of this side project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By listening to other people, it’s helped with my writing and making it more conversational. I get ideas for blog posts like this one and get to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/shanerice/status/501845460617670656&quot;&gt;share the advice and inspiration&lt;/a&gt; with other people. I’ve traded emails with people I respect like &lt;a href=&quot;http://sivers.org/&quot;&gt;Derek Sivers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All because it was no longer mandatory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s sparked other ideas for more side projects too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tom-haverfoods-meets-dale-carnegie&quot;&gt;Tom Haverfoods Meets Dale Carnegie&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to hate reading in high school and college. Your assigned to read to chapter 13 by next Tuesday or 250 pages by the end of the week. It was mandatory. And no fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After college, I found myself reading more. I would rip through a book in a weekend and enjoy every minute of it. Because it wasn’t mandatory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I could recommend any book to you it would be &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/How-Win-Friends-Influence-People/dp/0671027034&quot;&gt;How to Win Friends and Influence People&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; by Dale Carnegie. Ignore the cheesy title. It’s timeless lessons in how to be considerate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carnegie has 30 principles in the book. Smile. Try honestly to see things from the other person’s point of view. Ask questions instead of giving direct orders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem was finding all the principles in one place. Since the book was published in 1936, yes almost 80 years ago, it’s a bit outdated. I could find PDFs online and a list of the 30 principles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it just didn’t feel right. That’s when I found inspiration from an unexpected source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://draftin.com:443/images/20579?token=BXdG8RZM6u2oQDivbXOOgddjctw5KCOFajiljcwHqCHEldkfVvnjTbCVoLzQ_p9tv5s8JLb_C4kFn3M3GHufeZA&quot; alt=&quot;tomhaverfoods.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parks and Rec is a hilarious sitcom. Aziz Ansari’s character has a &lt;a href=&quot;http://youtu.be/m3wQftmEDu0&quot;&gt;skit&lt;/a&gt; where he fires off different slang for foods. And then someone made the site, &lt;a href=&quot;http://youtu.be/m3wQftmEDu0&quot;&gt;tomhaverfoods.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reload the site and you’ll see a new slang term. Honey is bear drool. Ice cream is milk on the rocks. Milk is cereal sauce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://youtu.be/3oLuxhYO5cw?t=1m40s&quot;&gt;It’s amazing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found it really interesting how the site was built. It’s so simple. Just one phrase per page. How did they do that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s when I decided to marry to the two ideas. What if Tom Haverfoods could work for Dale Carnegie’s principles?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now I give to you, &lt;a href=&quot;http://dalecarnegieismyhomeboy.com/&quot;&gt;dalecarnegieismyhomeboy.com&lt;/a&gt;. Reload the page and find a new principle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This side project taught me how to build a site that delivers dynamic content when the page reloads. Javascript is boring, but man is it useful. I practiced writing code and designing a website too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All skills that help me learn. And all because reading was no longer mandatory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tim Wakefield wasn’t going to make it to the Major Leagues as a power hitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Woody Huyke was a scout for the Pittsburgh Pirates. He noticed Wakefield throwing that knuckleball around in Spring Training. Then he asked Wakefield to throw it off the mound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wakefield pitched 19 years in the Major Leagues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He won 200 games on the mound throwing that knuckleball. A feat only 112 pitchers have ever accomplished. He struck out over 2,000 batters. And he won two World Series titles with the Red Sox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t mandatory for Tim Wakefield to throw the ball straight. So on the side and during practice, he threw it a different way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Find the things in your life that are no longer mandatory. Do them on the side. And you might just discover your knuckleball.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/mandatory/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/mandatory/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Few Words About Transparency</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“This isn’t even the rental application,” she confessed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I contended, “40 minutes late, and didn’t even give us the right information. Wow.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The place is perfect, though. It’s exactly what we both want.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She was right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The place was a one bedroom condo in Arlington, VA in a brand new building. It’s across from a grocery store. Within steps to several restaurants. Spacious. And for a solid price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An hour earlier, we saw a basement apartment. It’s a small, segmented space. The fridge, toilet, and window are so close you could a run a triple-option. No chance our furniture could fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The places were different. And so were the people behind them. The first is managed by a large, real-estate company. The apartment was an old nanny’s suite in the basement of someone’s home. It was part of her house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My girlfriend and I needed to make a decision where to live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which place did we choose?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a lot of noise around the word transparency. It’s become a &lt;a href=&quot;http://adage.com/article/the-media-guy/media-marketing-buzzwords-die/294521/&quot;&gt;buzzword&lt;/a&gt;. Companies tout, “we value transparency.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what does transparency really mean?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a look at a definition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;transparent (adj.) -  easy to see through, understand, or recognize; obvious; open; frank; candid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do what you say. Share what you know. Tell the truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is transparent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our generation believes in it. We are used to sharing everything. And we want the companies we deal with to do the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there is a lack of information, we assume you’re hiding something from us. We tell people what we think - good or bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s starting to be adopted in business too. Buffer is a young company that is an open-book. Buffer shares &lt;a href=&quot;https://buffer.baremetrics.io/dashboard&quot;&gt;financials&lt;/a&gt;, employee’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://open.bufferapp.com/introducing-open-salaries-at-buffer-including-our-transparent-formula-and-all-individual-salaries/&quot;&gt;salaries&lt;/a&gt;, and even their &lt;a href=&quot;http://b.fastcompany.net/multisite_files/fastcompany/inline/2013/05/3009585-inline-inline-1-7-slightly-crazy-ways-to-build-a-happy-productive-and-transparent-company.jpg&quot;&gt;sleep cycles&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People buy from other people for three reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They know you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They like you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They &lt;u&gt;trust&lt;/u&gt; you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can spend money for people to know you. Companies buy attention all the time. Advertising?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can be funny and generous to get people to like you. If we get &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slideshare.net/bradfrostweb/death-to-bullshit/67&quot;&gt;1,000 likes&lt;/a&gt; on Facebook we’ll donate to an orphanage. Lame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you get people to trust you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make the other person feel important - and do so sincerely. Try honestly to see things from the other person’s point of view. Ask questions instead of giving direct orders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do what you say. Share what you know. Tell the truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be transparent. And you’ll earn people’s trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, when your company is hacked and the personal information of your customers is comprised, it can shatter trust. That didn’t happen to Buffer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://draftin.com:443/images/20240?token=zZuphi4EVlUOd0QS1a2aJoRnBpzRAeyT4RvQfPN8Z-8YYktOAPiCpRCIAwr17qFz_lWud6hgM0Vzr06ToEtj7qg&quot; alt=&quot;bufferapp-transparency.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because Buffer does what it says its going to do. They share what they know. And tell the truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, Buffer lost customers. But several people stuck with them because they trust Buffer. The young company continues to grow, nearing $4 million dollars in revenue a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People share their money with other people they trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jason Fried and Jeffrey Zeldman explore this topic on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.muleradio.net/thebigwebshow/106/&quot;&gt;The Big Web Show Podcast&lt;/a&gt;. Jason shares a story about shopping for a car. He had a choice of where to buy the car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He could pick a local dealer that could give him the car instantly. But that dealer’s salesman rubbed him the wrong way. He didn’t treat him well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or he could wait 30 days, and buy from a dealer in Chattanooga, TN. This car salesman was smart, informative, and made Jason feel important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So which car did he buy?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jason explains how someone told him something that completely changed his perspective on money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Every dollar is a vote. And when you spend your dollars, you’re voting for the things that you want to see more of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Jason Fried, &lt;a href=&quot;Two Jews Talking About Business&quot;&gt;Two Jews Talking About Business&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jason waited 30 days and bought the car from the dealer in Chattanooga. Because he wants more people like that salesman in the world. He voted for him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Trust.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So which place did we choose to live?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out the real estate company was shady. Shenanigans. Hidden application and move-in fees. Two people gave us two different answers about how much parking cost. Terrible reviews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, thanks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After visiting the basement apartment, we exchanged emails with the owner of the home. She asked more questions about us - as people. She shared places to eat in the area. And more about herself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She was transparent. And she got our vote.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/transparency/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/transparency/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What is Time?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;What is time?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time is money. There are timelines and timetables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overtime. Uptime. Downtime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daytime and nighttime. Dinnertime and lunchtime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can waste time. And you can make time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You wish you had the time. To save time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Free time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what is time?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;draft&quot;&gt;Draft&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nathan Kontny has a &lt;a href=&quot;http://ninjasandrobots.com/how-to-get-business-ideas-remove-steps&quot;&gt;simple theory&lt;/a&gt; about how to get business ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Find a job people have.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;List out every step people take to complete that job.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove as many steps as you can.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is how Kontny built &lt;a href=&quot;https://draftin.com/&quot;&gt;Draft&lt;/a&gt;. Draft is a web app that makes you write better through  easy collaboration and version control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He describes how he would send his wife blog posts for her to edit and he realized how many steps were involved in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As I would watch her operate, I would send her a link to a blog post. She would copy and paste it all into Microsoft Word. And then she would do her stuff. Then she would send me a Word document back over email. I have to open up Word now or Pages, something on my Mac, which was awful. I have to copy and paste the work she had done back into a text editor or whatever. It was just like here is eight steps or however many I just labeled. It’s too many steps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Nathan Kontny, &lt;a href=&quot;http://productpeople.tv/2014/07/24/ep61-nate-kontny/&quot;&gt;Solve Your Own Problems, Product TV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kontny eliminates several steps. He built Draft to send a link to his wife and she could edit it within the browser. He could then accept the changes he wanted or reject those he did not want. And that’s it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://draftin.com:443/images/19974?token=3a8utu0GnmQ23ZDm6Cv-4iZWrkuXuCrKUkdj9Fx8k-cMVmB3ID8uTarsHIU616WxqU2htW-oRPv72lL4JpfBUVk&quot; alt=&quot;Draft-share-link-app.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By eliminating steps Kontny has solved his own problem and one that was a major pain for other people too. Draft gives you a little bit of time back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s the real value. You no longer have to waste time of opening Microsoft Word or be confused with Google Docs. No more copying and pasting into other programs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Draft is selling time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;uber&quot;&gt;Uber&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week I needed to hitch a ride to Union Station in Washington DC to catch the Megabus at 7:00 am. I live about four miles from the Metro in Arlington, VA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could of called a taxi or started walking towards the Metro. And then ride the Metro into Union Station to catch the bus. But it was 5:45 am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead I packed up my things and pulled up Uber on my phone. I live in a residential neighborhood. I requested a ride and poured a bowl of cereal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I could take the second scoop from the bowl, the driver had already arrived at my apartment. He was backed into the driveway and ready to take me to Union Station. It cost just $15 and I arrived with 30 minutes to spare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favorite part about Uber is how you pay the driver. Let’s compare the payment process with a taxi and Uber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://draftin.com:443/images/19975?token=4T2lcfeYuu0_lBdLUqt8nZYekJLFJ2_lUdANhPdFJChwkiCfPDDsiHQyb7oj98R0DVKfP4zsHlhIg315o8Lx37I&quot; alt=&quot;uber-image.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not always that bad. But it can be. There is not a standard rate for taxis. Some only take cash. Others can’t take certain cards. Inconvenient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uber slashes the steps in half. It eliminated at least three steps for me that morning and gave me some time back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uber is selling time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;napster&quot;&gt;Napster&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This idea of eliminating steps has been around for a while. Remember Napster? Go down memory lane and watch the documentary &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/2013/03/exclusive-clip-napster-doc-downloaded/&quot;&gt;Downloaded&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company shattered the music industry. Napster was a catalyst for social networks and proved how technology was going to change our lives forever. How did you get new music before 1999?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s list out the steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go to your local record store.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Search for the artist’s CD or record.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Buy the full CD or record.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take it to your car or home.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Play the music.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shawn Fanning, Sean Parker, and the rest of the Napster crew obliterated that process. Here’s how you could get new music with Napster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Open your computer and the Napster app.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Search for the artist’s music.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click download and play the music.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/KMzAetFgx2I&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could do this all from your dorm room. Millions of people did. Because Napster would save you lots of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Music will be ubiquitous. And we believe you’ll be able to get it on your cell phone, on your stereo, or whatever the device of the future is. I think people are going to be willing to pay for convenience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Sean Parker, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.billboard.com/biz/articles/news/digital-and-mobile/1552508/qa-sean-parker-and-shawn-fanning-on-downloaded-the&quot;&gt;Downloaded&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Napster was selling time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what is time? It’s our most valuable resource.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And today, you can buy it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because time is for sale.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-is-time/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-is-time/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Confessions of a Beginner</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This week I put a new coat of paint on my personal website - &lt;a href=&quot;http://hotdogsandeggs.com&quot;&gt;hotdogsandeggs.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote the code from scratch for the first time. It’s effective not elegant. I’m sure there are things I could simplify or improve. If you recognize something that could be better, please let me know &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cjagllo&quot;&gt;@cjgallo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a beginner. And this is what I learned writing the code on my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;its-not-scary&quot;&gt;It’s Not Scary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;HTML is just going around with a label maker and throwing labels on everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://people.hotdogsandeggs.com/2014/02/01/jessica-hische/&quot;&gt;Jessica Hische, Learn the Tools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jessica Hische is a designer. And she preaches how you must learn the tools to make the things you want to make. HTML is not scary or intimidating. You just throw a label on things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://draftin.com:443/images/19285?token=bvXoOlz6HkSUab8ZTklLvMXKnGdAw4JbCbsjaEfvSTVgCcoNwe6phRCuqUqgInUQKDw0FEU9lwLbkQ2yL_OrGDM&quot; alt=&quot;funny-css.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rasheed Wallace. Shaq. Muggsy Bogues. Randolph Childress. These are not just great basketball players. But the labels I used when creating the site. They live in a CSS file titled, you guessed it, Tim Duncan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is proof that you just throw labels on everything. This makes it easier for me to understand how CSS and HTML work together. Plus, it creates a comfortable feeling because you can name things what you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not scary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rip-something-off&quot;&gt;Rip Something Off&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://humblepied.com/jim-coudal/&quot;&gt;Jim Cloudal believes&lt;/a&gt; you should find something you like and rip it off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is unorthodox advice. But it teaches you how things you like that are made and how you can re-create them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Jim, I ripped off his typography on &lt;a href=&quot;http://coudal.com/&quot;&gt;Cloudal Partners&lt;/a&gt;. The headlines and sub-headings have an old-school feel of a newspaper. With thousands of fonts available today, it’s refreshing what you can do with times new roman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://draftin.com:443/images/19286?token=uh3D26Qw5h5bUTgiSRSecnsyPPSu4dBYvLiuwUrEKYuLSk7qTt8CFK5kv0q06V-rF9G_v42ydf1FJdOzgy6uBus&quot; alt=&quot;cloudal-typography.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The letter spacing is really what makes this typography so beautiful. It’s easy to read and catches your eye. I’ve used it on the homepage, &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.hotdogsandeggs.com/&quot;&gt;my blog&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://http://people.hotdogsandeggs.com/&quot;&gt;another project&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another design I sought to rip off was from Frank Chimero. He uses a grid layout of to showcase &lt;a href=&quot;http://frankchimero.com/talks/&quot;&gt;his talks&lt;/a&gt;. The full-width squares or boxes was something that I really wanted to learn how to make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After toying with re-creating Frank’s design, I realized the squares were not something that was necessary for me. I have four things I want someone to know when they visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://hotdogsandeggs.com&quot;&gt;hotdogsandeggs.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What hot dogs and eggs is&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I share what I know on my blog - &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.hotdogsandeggs.&quot;&gt;blog.hotdogsandeggs.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They can find inspiration from my project - &lt;a href=&quot;http://people.hotdogsandeggs.com&quot;&gt;people.hotdogsandeggs.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And who I am - a short bio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of squares I split the site into these four sections using the full-width design that mirrors Frank’s design. It’s a class titled &lt;em&gt;shaq&lt;/em&gt; that includes these styles:
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;max-width: none;
  margin: 0;
  padding: 0;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is nothing wrong with ripping something off to help you learn. As Frank states on his site, “Be nice. Give credit. Share, don’t steal.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;email-is-a-great-way-to-learn&quot;&gt;Email is a Great Way to Learn&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lots of people want to kill email or declare it’s dying. It’s simply not true. As &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2014/08/why-email-will-never-die/375973/&quot;&gt;Alex Madrigal describes&lt;/a&gt;, email is “the cockroach of the Internet.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not going anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing an HTML email is different. It’s based on a lot of old standards and there is a lot that you cannot do. But you can use  inline styles. This means the CSS is written in combination with the HTML.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can be exhausting, but I find it to be a great way to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/RodriguezCommaJ&quot;&gt;Jason Rodriguez&lt;/a&gt; delivers a &lt;a href=&quot;http://alistapart.com/article/can-email-be-responsive&quot;&gt;great explanation&lt;/a&gt; of how to write and design an HTML email. He describes why HTML sucks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It’s like getting into a time machine and stepping out into a hellish ’90s world of table-based layouts, inline styles, non-semantic markup, and client-specific hacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://alistapart.com/article/can-email-be-responsive&quot;&gt;Jason Rodriguez, Can Email be Responsive?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the annoyances of writing code for email comes lots of opportunity to learn. For example, using &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rodriguezcommaj/salted&quot;&gt;Salted&lt;/a&gt; - a responsive template from Jason and &lt;a href=&quot;https://litmus.com/&quot;&gt;Litmus&lt;/a&gt; - I discovered ways to build bulletproof buttons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a beginner, I thought a fancy button must always be an image. Since lots of email clients strip images, the bulletproof button approach makes a lot of sense when writing an HTML email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://draftin.com:443/images/19287?token=ZLMu3XAnhOedYifGvcAeCLI-BF8R0F3idZ1UODSHFh3txg6vSoiZCpYX1e0u5Sp18CNMCkRLZldYuuzRjHIx-gU&quot; alt=&quot;people-hotdogsandeggs.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using CSS instead, I discovered how to make beautiful buttons without using an image. You will find the same types of buttons on my site that you will in the Salted email template.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reading through &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pinterest.com/pin/553802085401758894/&quot;&gt;an example&lt;/a&gt; of the Salted template, you also find it’s easy to digest information too. This design inspired me to re-create something similar for my site. Four sections with clear calls to action and easy to digest language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, writing an HTML email is a pain. But it forces you to understand how code works and why you should use specific approaches in certain situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s an awesome way to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-whats-next&quot;&gt;So What’s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning to code is not easy. But it’s so rewarding when you build something that makes you proud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a ton more for me to learn. And I can’t wait.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/beginner-confessions/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/beginner-confessions/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>You Can't Rely on Efficiency Alone</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Re-routing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s what I heard traveling home from the mountains. I knew where I was going. I just got off the interstate and was headed home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than turn off the Google Maps app, I left it on. And it didn’t agree with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Re-routing. Five seconds past. Re-routing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s as if the lady wanted to jump through the phone and say, “why are you going this way? It takes twice as long.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Re-routing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Straight line. You hear that this is the fastest route between to points. It’s the most efficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you drive do you always take the fastest route? The interstate or the highway? Maybe the freeway?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or do you take the scenic route sometimes? The backroads? Or the “long way”?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And what route do companies take? You always want them to take the fastest, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instant gratification. You want your item shipped now. The red light to turn green. And a response to your text message immediately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Efficiency wins. That’s what we were taught. Henry Ford once said, “efficient industry is the sole key to prosperity.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I would say companies that are just transactional, that are at this point just relying on things like efficiency, are probably going to be missing something in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://people.hotdogsandeggs.com/2014/07/30/valerie-coulton/&quot;&gt;Valerie Coulton&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Valerie Coulton is right. Coulton and Alistair Croll &lt;a href=&quot;http://tiltthewindmill.com/innovation-culture-and-design-valerie-coulton/&quot;&gt;explore the idea&lt;/a&gt; of servant leadership and how companies must disrupt themselves. Because efficiency is not the only thing that matters anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coulton continues, “if you don’t somehow feel that they [companies] take some interest in at least your satisfaction or in your comfort, and if not your delight, then I think they’re in danger.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;amazon&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amazon breathes efficiency. Fast delivery. One click purchases. Robot run fulfillment centers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its built an empire on being efficient. Amazon pays attention to customer service too. It makes clever recommendations for books and keeps you happy with free shipping. Its new &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html?nodeId=201349900&quot;&gt;MayDay button&lt;/a&gt; delivers instant face-to-face customer service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amazon is a transactional company. It relies on efficiency. Is it in danger?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kindle Unlimited is a new service from Amazon. You can pay $9.99 a month for all you can read (and listen) books. An interesting approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can try the service for one month free of charge. Why not? Upon signing up for Kindle Unlimited, I received an email that prompted me to get started. With one click, tons of books were at my fingertips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The choices were dead simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://draftin.com:443/images/18685?token=8J6Fd-hTBkidDDJLvZls_QJA9X_e_CL1IrxQjQ73ds588H70s_ZSzxmoOn5nolrSyELT4syx7p5-flJuMy1Xeec&quot; alt=&quot;amazon-efficient.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read for free. Buy with 1-Click. Give as a gift.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Efficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kindle Unlimited is a solid service. But after a week passed, and I was still plugging away reading one book, I knew it wasn’t going to worth the $9.99 a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was time to cancel. First, I traveled to Amazon and attempted to cancel my free trial. No dice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, I re-opened the original email and scanned for how to cancel or any information on the free trial. Below is the fine print I found in the email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Your Kindle Unlimited subscription will continue after your free trial until cancelled. If you do not wish to continue for $9.99/month plus any applicable taxes, you may cancel anytime by visiting Your Account and adjusting your subscription settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I found myself searching for the “Your Account” section on Amazon. A few more minutes passed. Couldn’t find my “subscription settings” either. Frustrated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Re-routing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I headed over to twitter and searched “how to cancel Kindle Unlimited”. And I found this tweet from &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/InternetPatrol&quot;&gt;@TheInternetPatrol&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://draftin.com:443/images/18687?token=uDIi07KqM9uG_GiNyfkGuoq8Y8Iyh5F6SkZRWpadAeL4W2nNAmPmrS0BJkbevKmFisfQj3VzA2bdmYHEMyIgED0&quot; alt=&quot;cancel-kindle-unlimited.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theinternetpatrol.com/how-to-cancel-the-kindle-unlimited-service-on-amazon/?utm_source=dlvr.it&amp;amp;utm_medium=twitter&quot;&gt;step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to cancel this free trial. That’s absurd. A company that turns complicated into simple fails to make it easy to cancel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know, that’s Amazon doing their job. But bullshit. If Amazon can make me buy something in one click and deliver something to me via a drone, why does it take a six step guide to cancel a service?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It feels like Jeff Bezos is just laughing at me. And I’m not the only one. Just take a look at the comments of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theinternetpatrol.com/how-to-cancel-the-kindle-unlimited-service-on-amazon/?utm_source=dlvr.it&amp;amp;utm_medium=twitter&quot;&gt;The Internet Patrol guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://draftin.com:443/images/18689?token=rnW4Q6fD1M-6nLwj2DDoXi_kaiYkmhMw0MCNmZSaERKk7Up7FasRMMFoGOL2JgrCDHRCIlFrYfGer0LLefieU1w&quot; alt=&quot;internet-patrol-comments.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amazon is not taking any interest in our comfort. It’s transactional. Efficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can’t rely on efficiency alone anymore. Amazon is not in immediate danger, but are we starting to &lt;a href=&quot;http://stratechery.com/2014/losing-amazon-religion/?utm_content=buffer20231&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter.com&amp;amp;utm_campaign=buffer&quot;&gt;lose our religion&lt;/a&gt; toward the brand? Time will tell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Re-routing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I drove all the way home ignoring the lady on Google Maps begging me to go the more efficient route. Because I didn’t want to go home the fastest way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to drive by my old friend’s street that brings back crazy memories. The country roads that make feel comfortable. And the restaurant (Fiesta Grill) that I never go to anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scenic route is not the most efficient. But sometimes it’s the most satisfying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Companies need to re-route efficiency. And focus on feelings.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/efficiency-alone/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/efficiency-alone/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Expecting Expectations</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Cold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s 6:45 a.m. on a brisk February morning. You just got out of the pool. And it feels like you jumped through a glass window. Cold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You shuffle as fast as you can to the locker room. It’s time for a long, hot shower. You go to turn the shower knob and you wait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cold. You wait a few more seconds. Still cold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s worse - setting the wrong expectation or not setting one at all?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think. You’ve been promised something before and not received it. You’ve been let down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether someone was late to a meeting, a company failed to issue you a refund, or your landlord raised your rent - you know what it’s like to have your expectations shattered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I find my life is a lot easier the lower I keep my expectations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Bill Watterson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expectations. These are the fuzzy feelings you have about things. If she will say yes to go on a date with you. If you will or won’t get the job. If a company is hiding something from you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;scustomers-people-expectations&quot;&gt;&lt;s&gt;Customer&lt;/s&gt; People Expectations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expectations are everything when communicating with customers. Customers always have an expectation in mind - because customers are people. And businesses get choose how to deal with these expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set the right expectations and you might have a customer for life. Fail to meet the expectations you set and you’ll lose a customer fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hiding-price&quot;&gt;Hiding Price&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://draftin.com:443/images/18047?token=10c4-I7p7FZJRw3wa7QIA8J_gxjCn1PF4JfAIKChJNUX8dhJqVlGAQLXKaq3nGy9iOf9vf1AQThwW9x6BIINm1w&quot; alt=&quot;no-price.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The beautiful business model of selling software. No physical product. A subscription-based service. Cancel at any time. Thousands of startups tinker with this business model every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine explained his startup doesn’t list prices on their website. The company refuses to share a pricing page. A prospective buyer must request a quote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is the pricing plans are pre-determined. The company could easily choose to share what payment plan a prospect would fall into, but makes the effort to hide it. The young business is afraid competitors will use the pricing information against them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friend is part of the sales team. Guess the number one question she receives from prospective buyers? You guessed right - &lt;em&gt;what’s the price?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is nothing to gain by not sharing price. Because the customer already has an expectation. This person might be expecting double the price of the product or expect it to be dirt cheap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If price is a main concern, it’s likely the prospect is not a perfect fit for the product anyway. But by not sharing it, the business is refusing to face that expectation. This is a terrible first impression for a potential customer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without an expectation set on price, this young business is failing to understand its customers. Remember, customers are people. And people have expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cd-babys-shipping-policy&quot;&gt;CD Baby’s Shipping Policy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://draftin.com:443/images/18050?token=2gvYMLXGzLf-iiHW9CXSAq2b3g1GtfxDhNVk0j5sclSszLdCP_rMmVmRFwms2TXUxefyrOP25nwqfVHO44aGK1A&quot; alt=&quot;Screen Shot 2014-07-23 at 2.23.10 PM.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Derek Sivers loves to experiment. The founder of CD Baby, Sivers shares lots of his experiments in his book &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sivers.org/a&quot;&gt;Anything You Want&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. His &lt;a href=&quot;http://members.cdbaby.com/shipping-confirmation.aspx&quot;&gt;casual approach&lt;/a&gt; after someone submits an order and his &lt;a href=&quot;http://sivers.org/cs&quot;&gt;customer service philosophy&lt;/a&gt; are celebrated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because Derek understands the expectations of &lt;s&gt;customers&lt;/s&gt; people. He’s honest. He sees things from the other person’s point of view. And that helped him build a multi-million dollar business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his book, Derek recalls how customers would call and ask, “What time is it there? Do I still have time to get it sent today?” CD Baby would ship FedEx each day at 5 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Customers wanted to know when they could expect their order to be delivered. And what did Derek do? He set the expectation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;So I added two little lines of programming code that counted how many hours and minutes remained until 5 p.m. and then showed the result by the shipping options. “You have 5 hours, 18 minutes until our next FedEx shipment.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Derek Sivers, &lt;a href=&quot;http://sivers.org/a&quot;&gt;Anything You Want&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Derek shares that &lt;s&gt;customers&lt;/s&gt; people loved this. It’s easy to see why. CD Baby set an expectation and met that expectation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When businesses set expectations and met those expectations, &lt;s&gt;customers&lt;/s&gt; people are happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The shower never got hot that day. People complained to the front desk at the pool. One threatened to never come to the pool again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day a funny thing happened. When you walked into the building, the front desk had a sign that read, “No Hot Water Today. But we do have Hot Chocolate!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That simple expectation made a world of difference. It’s amazing how much easier a cold shower is when you know to expect it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;When your customers are expecting a hot shower, don’t give them a cold one.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/expectations/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/expectations/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Language You Use</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My father will forget more baseball than I will ever know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was a coach for decades. He taught me how to play the game. And specifically how to hit a baseball.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mechanics of hitting are the opposite of exciting. It’s a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/The-Science-Hitting-Ted-Williams/dp/0671621033&quot;&gt;science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a teenager, you never wanted to listen. You wanted the bat and to swing. That’s it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But coaches tried to teach the mechanics. All that jargon is overwhelming and boring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My father used to call it &lt;em&gt;paralysis by analysis&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how did he make the boring subject of hitting a baseball more interesting?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you talk like a scientist, only scientists will understand you. If you talk like a trucker, everyone will understand you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Simon Sinek&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The words you use are critical to communication. The more you use empty, boring words - the harder it will be to get your point across.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In customer support, our team must explain technical concepts to help customers get started using our product. An example, installing two blocks of Javascript onto your site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process is dull. But it’s the boring task you must complete to do all the cool things with the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choose your words carefully. Talk like a trucker. Not a scientist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;take-net-neutrality&quot;&gt;Take Net Neutrality&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is important topic. But it’s not simple to explain. Because the cable giants and FCC have buried it in boring language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John Oliver fixes all of that. On his new series &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/LastWeekTonight&quot;&gt;Last Week Tonight&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, he delivers a 13-minute rant on the importance of Net Neutrality. And he uses language that you can understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Net Neutrality. The only two words that cause more boredom in the english language are featuring Sting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of hiding behind the boring language, Oliver explains that it means all data has to be created equally no matter who created it. The Internet is a level playing field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An end to Net Neutrality means companies can out-spend others and create an unequal playing field. A fast lane for the privileged and slow lane for the have-nots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fast-lane-for-everybody-and-a-hyper-speed-lane-for-others&quot;&gt;Fast lane for everybody. And a hyper-speed lane for others.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;George Foote, a telecommunications lawyer, says fast lane and slow lane is not true. It really should be fast lane and hyper-speed lane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oliver calls bullshit on this boring explanation. He says it won’t be Usain Bolt and Usain Bolt on a motor-bike. It will be Usian Bolt and Usian Bolt-ed to an anchor. Colorful language that’s easy to understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://draftin.com:443/images/17753?token=lW4JuuYBf9wqIY21u_XbolHeEPkauYHulcOTkYlMV9XQeoK9MHjihkUlnfpojwDS_8J2fm3eKkXEdqHond1_g0U&quot; alt=&quot;last-week-tonight-usian-bolt.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-dingo-as-a-babysitter&quot;&gt;A dingo as a babysitter.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;President Obama tabbed John Wheeler, a former top lobbyist for cable and telecommunications companies, to be the next chair of the FCC. He used to fight for these companies and now he gets to regulate them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All boring language. That’s why Oliver explains it as the equivalent of needing a babysitter and hiring a dingo. You can get how ridiculous that is because Oliver chooses words you can understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://draftin.com:443/images/17755?token=uWyy8XOhRi5rarecSJ3AOCNLZhbDrfyetYgY2GesWPhA9Gn6WkX_S2JQag6CJknT74t-9-dJH0Uk4JMclkUX4jA&quot; alt=&quot;last-week-tonight-dingo-babysitter.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;preventing-cable-company-fckery&quot;&gt;Preventing cable company f*ckery.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oliver shares a clip, where the government uses the following language: &lt;em&gt;it seeks comment on ways to construe additional language in section 706, and even suggests using section 230B to broaden the scope of the commissions authority&lt;/em&gt;. That’s the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you want to do something evil, put it into something boring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;John Oliver, Last Week Tonight&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oliver makes the amazing example that Apple could put the entire text of Mein Kampf in the user agreement and you would just click agree. This leads Oliver to abandon the term Net Neutrality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just call it preventing cable company f*ckery. That’s not boring. And it tells the whole story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://draftin.com:443/images/17757?token=_ta9E08D_0TIGT7nesGMT9TTLq4MucOYbYypMA-XOIDeHOTadDbMjEzGOfAx_akxc_-9EMWtkKIMw28VPSbS8vc&quot; alt=&quot;last-week-tonight-net-neutrality.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure you &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fpbOEoRrHyU&amp;amp;feature=kp&quot;&gt;watch the whole clip here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slap the midget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s how my father made the boring subject of hitting a baseball more interesting. A simple phrase that causes you to turn your head and let out a chuckle. (No harm or discrimination is meant by it).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a way to make the hitter properly use his bottom hand to swing through the ball. Words that demand attention and deliver the message in language you can understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Talk like a trucker. Because no one likes boring language.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/langauge-you-use/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/langauge-you-use/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Medium &gt; Message</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You have an amazing amount of ways to communicate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phone call. Email. Face-to-face. Text message. Video. Tweet. Snapchat. Skype. Vine. Instagram. And so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are all mediums to send your message. But is the medium becoming more important than the message?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Marketing is a subjective thing. It’s not a science. There is a lot of art to it. My personal belief is that the medium really does communicate a lot about the message. In some cases, the medium overrides the message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Steve Jobs, &lt;a href=&quot;http://youtu.be/3LEXae1j6EY?t=46m50s&quot;&gt;Messages &amp;amp; Mediums&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Substitute marketing for communication. It’s all subjective. As much as you believe things are black and white - they’re not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s full of colors. Perceptions. Assumptions. And feelings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without changing the message, the medium can radically change how you feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;heres-a-simple-example&quot;&gt;Here’s a simple example&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;animated-gifs--static-imagestext&quot;&gt;Animated Gifs &amp;amp; Static Images/Text&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ve stumbled across the message before when surfing the web. A 404 page. It means you’re on a page that no longer exists or at a broken link. It’s the most common error message on the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simple message. But the medium makes an enormous difference in how you feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take &lt;a href=&quot;http://mlb.com/404&quot;&gt;mlb.com/404&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://espn.com/404&quot;&gt;espn.com/404&lt;/a&gt; as an example. Both sites present the same error message. The page you tried to visit doesn’t exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-does-the-espn-example-make-you-feel&quot;&gt;How does the ESPN example make you feel?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ads are not going to help here. The page features tons of links and a search bar. But this message is just plain and ordinary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://img.svbtle.com/wpxtlnj95o4gma.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/wpxtlnj95o4gma_small.png&quot; alt=&quot;espn404.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;now-what-about-the-mlb-example&quot;&gt;Now what about the MLB example?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The medium of an animated gif entertains you. This makes you smile. You almost want to refresh the page to see the next blunder. It’s a brilliant way to deliver a simple message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://draftin.com:443/images/17017?token=0WocXh1Y1FnVck5kZ1VXNo8-Y3-a5aCoPZQ6jwKtGl7H-F6xPBsNYpjBqta-phN0R-AhjeRiUWeF_5yYKcyQAoY&quot; alt=&quot;mlb-404.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steve Jobs’ answer was about Apple’s advertising. If you continue to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3LEXae1j6EY&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&amp;amp;t=46m50s&quot;&gt;watch the video&lt;/a&gt;, you will hear Jobs explain why Apple should avoid television or commercials this year (1997).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Television creates the perception that Apple needs to spend money to convince you everything was on the right track. At the time, Apple needed to use the medium of print media to talk about it’s products and customers in a straight-forward way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because it changes how people feel about the company. Apple is not trying to convince us. They’re being real and honest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same is true for you. What medium you choose for communication has a lot more impact than you think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of sending a PDF of your cover letter. Make a video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than texting your parents. Call and tell them you love them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t ask someone to ‘connect’ on LinkedIn. Grab a cup coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Because the medium beats the message.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/medium-message/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/medium-message/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Don't Be a Robot, Create Conversations</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a guest post published on &lt;a href=&quot;http://supportops.co/&quot;&gt;SupportOps&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tour guide wipes his brow. And wonders how to respond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A chubby teenager, my eyelashes batted a few times.  Blank stares colored the faces of everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What just happened?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;San Antonio. A tour of the Alamo. You’ll never guess the question this guy asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://supportops.co/dont-be-a-robot-create-conversations/&quot; class=&quot;about-me&quot;&gt;What was it?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/create-conversations/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/create-conversations/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Of Course, But Maybe</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Of course. But maybe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Louis CK has a fantastic theory. It goes like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Everybody has a competition in their brain of good thoughts and bad thoughts. Hopefully, the good thoughts win. For me, I always have both. I have like, the thing, I believe the good thing, that’s the thing I believe and than there is this thing. And I don’t believe it, but it is there. It’s always this thing and then this thing. It’s become a category in my brain that I call “of course but maybe.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Louis CK - &lt;a href=&quot;http://youtu.be/bkjmzEEQUlE?t&quot;&gt;Of Course, But Maybe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a &lt;a href=&quot;http://youtu.be/bkjmzEEQUlE?t=1m43s&quot;&gt;concrete example&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now how it applies to customer service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;cancel&quot;&gt;Cancel&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time Warner Cable. No one is fond of this company. And their is a laundry list of reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m moving this month and was ready to cancel my internet services. I do not have cable. And as much as that blows the minds of Time Warner representatives, they fail to treat me any differently or even in &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cjgallo/status/429023436392767488&quot;&gt;my native language&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides the point. Go to Time Warner Cable’s website right now and try to cancel your account. The process is full of frustration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have to search how to cancel. It’s not clear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can cancel a service, but not your account, by chatting with a customer service representative. Account cancellations must be processed through a customer service representative and cannot be initiated online.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you can bill online. You can shop online. Make an appointment online. But can’t cancel online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a 13 minute call with Time Warner Cable, you’re re-routed several times before speaking to someone you can help. The account is finally canceled. But you’re phone looks like a &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cjgallo/status/474672908208701442/photo/1&quot;&gt;baby was using the keypad&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/tdsbjcvitlkteg_small.png&quot; alt=&quot;timewarner.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why not just let people cancel online? It’s a simple process. One that might bring them back again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, Time Warner Cable doesn’t want customers to cancel. But maybe, if they make it near impossible to cancel - customers will never want to do business with them again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;unsubscribe&quot;&gt;Unsubscribe&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not a favorable word for anyone who is involved in email marketing. But it happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is it so hard to unsubscribe? But easy to subscribe?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when you unsubscribe, you receive another email to confirm that you wanted to unsubscribe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s get this straight. You opt-out of the email list. You make an effort to say - &lt;em&gt;“stop emailing me.”&lt;/em&gt; So people just decide to email you again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jordanmunson/status/475015842963288064&quot;&gt;spell out this frustration&lt;/a&gt;. And some have even &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/better-gmail-unsubscribe/hdkbhdodcejjjicmnmhhibenjmlgmkfc&quot;&gt;built Chrome extensions&lt;/a&gt; to help you unsubscribe. Shenanigans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s something so easy, yet companies make it so hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if companies sent an email that looks like this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/zjv363x13ayq_small.png&quot; alt=&quot;unsubscribe-gmail.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure lots of people will unsubscribe. But the ones that didn’t are probably you’re most valuable customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, people don’t want you to unsubscribe from their email newsletter. Of course, they don’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But maybe, if unsubscribing from your email list is like completing a puzzle - people won’t unsubscribe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or maybe they will never subscribe again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;credit-card-required&quot;&gt;Credit Card Required&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Free trials. It’s common in software products. Like a drug dealer. You get a taste of the product for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But why do companies want your credit card for the trial?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prezi hits people with a $159 charge at the end of their free 30 day trial. It’s outlined with sketchy &lt;a href=&quot;https://prezi.com/support/article/account/trial-period-faq/?lang=en&quot;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;, but it’s still not fair. The charge is for an annual fee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did we not agree on a month free? This leaves people &lt;a href=&quot;https://getsatisfaction.com/prezi/topics/req_for_refund_trial_cancelled_but_still_got_charged_159?topic-reply-list%5Bsettings%5D%5Bfilter_by%5D=all&amp;amp;topic-reply-list%5Bsettings%5D%5Breply_id%5D=12136820#reply_12136820&quot;&gt;feeling abused&lt;/a&gt;. It shatters trust at the first impression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lincoln Murphy &lt;a href=&quot;http://sixteenventures.com/saas-free-trial-credit-card&quot;&gt;details&lt;/a&gt; how requiring a credit card does more harm than good. An example is through &lt;a href=&quot;http://hookfeed.com/&quot;&gt;Hookfeed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hookfeed might be a phenomenal product (never used it). It delivers Stripe analytics to its customers. It might even be a case where a credit card is required. The product is directly related to billing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Requiring a credit card lost &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/chrimack/status/474372874241716224&quot;&gt;them a sale&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/p9uulhldllkza_small.png&quot; alt=&quot;hookfeed.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, you want people to pay for your product. But maybe, if you require a credit card upfront, you will trick them into buying it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or maybe you will never earn their business in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stop making the easy things hard for your customers.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/of-course-but-maybe/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/of-course-but-maybe/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Unlikely Experience</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ma’m, how do you want your steak cooked? Oh, well-done. I would recommend medium-well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;No. Make it well-done. Thanks.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s not a fun conversation. You take the order, but the person wants their food cooked in a way that the chef doesn’t believe in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I took the order and sent the ticket back to the chef. And began the slow walk to kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve never been in a restaurant kitchen before, let me describe it. Four letter words. Chaos. Food in places it shouldn’t be. Weird phrases like 86 the halibut. Loud noises. And broken glass. Everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cringed and the chef ripped the ticket I just sent back. You see a well-done steak is just doing yourself a disservice. It’s not good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or as the chef put it - you should of told her to order fucking shoe leather. Fair enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He asked me to explain or convince the person not to order it well-done. Just try, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here goes nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A tuxedo. Credenzas. Tickets. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.foodservicewarehouse.com/update-international/tcg-6/p329831.aspx?utm_medium=cpc&amp;amp;utm_term=Update-International-TCG-6&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Table-Crumbers&amp;amp;utm_source=googlepla&amp;amp;source=googleps&amp;amp;gclid=CjgKEAjwwuqcBRCSuoivmIPnkwQSJACpqj3kDUDHAHPDuf-ZtPaKIeB9nz_JjQPHUGLDPRLHwVwMZvD_BwE&quot;&gt;Crumber&lt;/a&gt;. And lots of long hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I worked for a fancy restaurant for two years in college. Made lots of money. And spent it all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The experience has never been on my resume. Yet it’s the most relevant to any employer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;communication&quot;&gt;Communication&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about your job. Whether you’re an engineer, CEO, teacher, or salesman - it’s about communication. You have to know how to write. To listen. Ask questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Communication is the key. And that’s exactly what working in a restaurant teaches you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a waiter or waitress, you interact with the hostess, the chef, the bus boy, other wait staff, and the real live customer. These are all people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are people that can make your life difficult or easy. So you must communicate clearly and be friendly. It’s your only choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, the cooks are people too. Even the the ones who aren’t the chef. I’m talking the line cooks and people that work the fryer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of each night, as a waiter or waitress, you would be starving. Being around food all day and not eating is plain cruel. So after the shift, you had to get lucky to grab something from the kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or you could treat the line cooks like they were important. You could talk to them as if they were people. Even if they did speak another language. And at the end of night, you would have a sandwich ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first time I walked out with a sandwich already made for me, all the new wait staff was stunned.
How did you do that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s simple. I treat the line cooks like people. And communicate to them that they matter. The reward is a sandwich.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;overwhelmed&quot;&gt;Overwhelmed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever felt buried at work? Stressed out? Burned out? Like you’re in over your head?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try waiting on rude people for 6 hours. Juggle tickets and forget to punch in a order. Be on your feet and pour Shirley Temple refills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s pressure. And hard work. It feels like it will never end. Like you can’t do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sound familiar?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working in a restaurant forces you to learn how to keep your cool. Yes, this means you might lose your shit a couple times. But it also means you will be able to handle busy situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll understand that it’s ok if you screw up. You learn what you’re not good at. And how to ask for help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you help others, they will help you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;decisions&quot;&gt;Decisions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You get to make decisions every day. Whether you realize it or not, you’re in control of your choices. This means you might have to make tough decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firing an employee. Quitting your job. Telling a client no. Refusing to compromise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same types of decisions happen when working at a restaurant. You asked what do you recommend? You get to choose to upsell. Or be honest to customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You decide how to treat people. It comes down to choices. And you get to make the easy ones and the hard ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ma’m, I’m sorry but we’re not able to serve the steak well-done. Medium-well will give you the flavor you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see our chef prides himself on how he cooks this meat. He’s trained his whole life to deliver you an amazing meal. And serving the meat well-done crushes his pride.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just try it medium-well. If you don’t like it, we will pay for your entire table’s meal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;She loved it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next time someone asks how much experience you have, be sure to think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because odds are you have unlikely experience that is better than any internship or apprenticeship. It’s working with real people and developing soft skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t be afraid to share your experience. Even if it’s unlikely.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/unlikely-experience/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/unlikely-experience/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Be Specific</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Stop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Singing at the top of his lungs, windows down, a careless teenager approaches a stop sign. But he doesn’t halt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He slows down. And rolls right through it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A police officer crosses the intersection and the two cars smack together like bumper boats. Except no one is on the water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cop accelerates forward and flips his car around in a complete 180. And the blue lights flash to pull the man over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dinged up passenger door of the cop car flies open. And the officer jumps out, fists clinched, ready to enforce the law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The teenager awkwardly awaits feeling like he just got cut off at karaoke. Rushing as a linebacker would a quarterback, the police officer shouts - &lt;em&gt;“what do you do at a stop sign?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scared adolescent mumbles, &lt;em&gt;“slow down.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you follow directions? Or do you like coloring outside the lines?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your day is filled with people trying to get you to do something. Whether it’s your spouse asking you to take out the trash, your professor asking you to submit homework, or your boss asking for her report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People demand action. Yet people fail to be specific.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You say please let us know if you have any questions. Instead of &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.hotdogsandeggs.com/2014/05/12/ask-questions/&quot;&gt;asking a specific question&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buy our product. Why? It’s better. Really? Why is it better? Specifically, what makes it better?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the infamous, cable company. We will be at your house between noon and 5 p.m. That’s terrible. Unreliable. And just plan careless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A beautiful example of the difference between being specific and ambiguous comes from Simon Sinek. Watch this two minute and thirty-seven second clip as he explains the importance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without direction you’ll end up no where.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/c6PKDmWqjIs&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specific is clear. It builds trust. And it makes it personal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the difference in being respected and ignored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##What Happens when you’re not specific&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;General Motors is in a crisis. The bureaucratic company is recalling more cars than it’s selling - that’s a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s doesn’t help that the company is not specific about its recalls. Over 2 million cars with the same defects were not recalled until &lt;em&gt;a decade&lt;/em&gt; after the issue was found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the company was specific, the failed mass production of the cars would not have occurred in the first place. The recalls would of happened a decade earlier. And the company wouldn’t be a walking embarrassment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;General Motors even went out of their way trying not to be specific - banning over 60 words that employees could not use. Watch as &lt;a href=&quot;http://youtu.be/j6IZ2TroruU&quot;&gt;John Oliver destroys&lt;/a&gt; General Motors ridiculous actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not being specific costs General Motors the trust of its customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##What Specific Can do for you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The restaurant serves one type of dish. It seats 10 people. The price of food starts at $300. And it’s sold out every night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why? It’s damn good sushi. And its chef, Jiro Ono, is specific.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I get on the train at the same time and enter the same spot, everyday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Jiro Ono, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.magpictures.com/jirodreamsofsushi/&quot;&gt;Jiro Dreams of Sushi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jiro Ono’s path to success starts with simple actions. Humans are creatures of habit. Jiro proves this with his routine when he gets on the train every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This routine is proof of the power of being specific. Exact is specific. The same time. The same spot. Jiro’s routine translates into how he cooks and runs his restaurant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One apprentice made a dish hundreds of times over the span of months. And every time it failed to meet Jiro’s specific standards. When the chef finally made the dish to his taste - he cried.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specific is not easy. But it make all the difference in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Slow down or stop?”&lt;/em&gt; The officer shouted back at the teenager. Again, the youngster claimed - &lt;em&gt;“I slow down.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cop reached for his belly club, and began swinging at the side mirror of the car knocking it out of whack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The teenager screamed - &lt;em&gt;“STOP!”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then cop asked a simple question. &lt;em&gt;“Do you want me to stop or slow down?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be specific.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/be-specific/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/be-specific/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Show, Don't Tell</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Show. Don’t tell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you were in school you didn’t talk about your pet rock in front of your classmates. You showed it to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a support rep, my days are spent trying to explain to people why they need to do something. Whether that is to use the product, update their billing information, or inspire them to try a different approach - it requires showing, not telling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s 3 tools to help you get your point across.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;skitch&quot;&gt;1. Skitch&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is free web app run by the Evernote. It makes it simple to mark-up a screenshot and explain yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever used Photoshop, Adobe Reader, or Keynote to mark-up documents - you know the struggle.  You jump through lots of hoops just to add an arrow or text to the image. You don’t need 12 steps - you need one or two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://evernote.com/skitch/&quot;&gt;Download Skitch&lt;/a&gt; and give yourself 10 minutes of your life back. Here’s a quick example of how easy it is to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, let me tell you what to do. After you read one of my blog posts, click the twitter hyperlink and tell me what you thought of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seems easy enough - right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now let me show you with Skitch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://draftin.com:443/images/15701?token=nq7-bkjYTjnSiuAcLIX-Dt5LQ8zE5-X3ZqaI-BnET2252NublJyIk-bJIvhmxDkBaotPFeawZMHmd0qXYdO82TA&quot; alt=&quot;skitch-example.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Which one is easier to understand?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;licecap&quot;&gt;2. LICEcap&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Animated gifs are all the rage. But this format can be useful in getting your message across in a simple way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nathan Kontny, creator of &lt;a href=&quot;http://draftin.com&quot;&gt;Draft&lt;/a&gt;, uses &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cockos.com/licecap/&quot;&gt;LICEcap&lt;/a&gt; to showcase new features he adds to his web app. Check out one of &lt;a href=&quot;http://ninjasandrobots.com/draft-announcements-better-sorting-duplicating-documents-and-more&quot;&gt;these announcements here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nate let me in on this trick after &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/natekontny/status/472056079581741056&quot;&gt;asking him on twitter&lt;/a&gt;. As he says, it’s such a simple and fast way to express a point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s check out an example. Remember the twitter example above where you could share or tell me what you think about my post on twitter? It’s time we adjust the styling of that line on the blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To do this you need open Google Chrome as your browser. Then scroll down underneath a blog post, and inspect element of where you’re asked to drop me a line of twitter. That’s telling you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cockos.com/licecap/&quot;&gt;LICEcap shows you&lt;/a&gt;. And it takes all of 2 minutes to put together. The image automatically saves to your computer as a gif.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://img.svbtle.com/liega0ebgsjtlq.gif&quot; alt=&quot;example-licecap.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quicktime-and-wistia&quot;&gt;3. Quicktime and Wistia&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This next tool was introduced to me by a customer. After going back and forth about installing a block of javascript, he decided to show me a 40 second clip of where he was placing the code. He used &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/quicktime/download/&quot;&gt;Quicktime&lt;/a&gt; to record his screen and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.screencast.com/&quot;&gt;Wistia&lt;/a&gt; to send the clip straight to my inbox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quicktime is built into MAC OS X and Wistia is free for up to 3 vidoes and 5 MB of bandwidth each month. It’s an easy way to show someone what you’re trying to accomplish, talk over the video to explain it, and create calls to action inside or after your video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s stick with the same example, but now we want to adjust the text for our twitter call to action at the end of each post.  Replace the text with - &lt;em&gt;Did you enjoy this post? Let me know on twitter?&lt;/em&gt; - using inspect element in Google Chrome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simple enough. But here’s how you can show someone how to do it using Quicktime and Wisita.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;//fast.wistia.net/embed/iframe/ec700cc91q?videoFoam=true&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; class=&quot;wistia_embed&quot; name=&quot;wistia_embed&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; oallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; msallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;//fast.wistia.net/assets/external/iframe-api-v1.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You brought your pet rock to show and tell for one reason. Because your classmates could see it with their own eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure - you can tell someone do something. But if you show them how to do something, they just might do it themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/show-dont-tell/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/show-dont-tell/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Breaking and Learning</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The late James Yancey is one of the greatest music producers of all-time. Known as J Dilla, you’ve heard his creations over legendary songs from - Tribe Called Quest, Janet Jackson, De la Soul, and many more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fellow producer, Madlib, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.spin.com/articles/madlib-video-interview-radio-france-vinyl-collection/&quot;&gt;compares him&lt;/a&gt; to jazz legend John Coltrane. Because everyone took something from J Dilla.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;J Dilla used lots of equipment like the MPC to make his music. But you’ll never guess how he learned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about a skill that you learned recently. It could be how to swim, drive a stick shift car, or maybe even cook a meal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How did you learn the skill? Did you read a manual or instructions? Did you instantly pick it up? Did you make a lot of mistakes?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or did you feel like you were going to drown? Did you stall the car? And burn the dinner?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you break it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The sexy piece of advice is to make things. What if we broke things instead? This is the process where you can learn so much more if you decide to learn from someone who’s done something great - and break it and take it apart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://youtu.be/noZJz3KVbGE?t=7m9s&quot;&gt;Mig Reyes, Creative Mornings - Backwards Advice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this insightful talk, Mig shares how he learned to code and build things. The advice he received was to &lt;a href=&quot;http://humblepied.com/jim-coudal/&quot;&gt;rip something off&lt;/a&gt; and if you’re not breaking things, you’re not trying hard enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because lessons won’t teach you how to swim. A manual can’t teach you how to drive stick. And a cook book won’t make the food taste better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You learn to swim by &lt;em&gt;swimming&lt;/em&gt;. You learn to drive stick by &lt;em&gt;driving&lt;/em&gt;. And you learn to cook by &lt;em&gt;cooking.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;J Dilla &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.complex.com/music/2011/02/10-facts-about-j-dilla-you-might-not-know#10&quot;&gt;never read&lt;/a&gt; an equipment manual. Detriot legend Amp Fiddler told Dilla not to read a book. You have to learn on your own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;J Dilla broke things. That’s how he learned. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xxlmag.com/news/2012/02/questlove-on-why-dilla-was-the-best-rap-producer-of-all-time/&quot;&gt;Quest Love even details&lt;/a&gt; how he recorded &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0zUFkQNBqoU&amp;amp;feature=kp&quot;&gt;Think Twice&lt;/a&gt; using a vibraphone mallet and broken drumstick wrapped in toliet paper and rubber bands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After losing a battle with lupus in 2006, his &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/snapjudgment/j-dillas-lost-scrolls&quot;&gt;mother was reunited&lt;/a&gt; with his record collection. You will appreciate &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rdio.com/people/MusicHype/playlists/581484/King_Of_The_Beats_J_Dilla_samples/&quot;&gt;his samples&lt;/a&gt; and how he broke down records transforming them into new music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do yourself a favor and listen to J Dilla.  And most of all learn from how he learned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next time you want to learn a new skill - break it down.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/break-and-learn/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/break-and-learn/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cut it in Half</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This week my workout was cut in half. Instead of 32 laps in the pool, it’s now just 16.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a major adjustment. One that is feels twice as hard. It’s funny - how can you cut something in half and it be twice as hard?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As humans, we’re not afraid to use words. Jargon. Buzzwords. Run-on sentences. Big words. Words with no meaning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schools train students that length is important. Five paragraph essays. 10 or 20 page papers. If you fill up a whole blue book, you feel more accomplished than if you just wrote one page. More is better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why? It’s easy to write more. To use fluff and ramble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s difficult to make every word count. To save space &lt;a href=&quot;http://signalvnoise.com/posts/1539-writing-decisions-saving-space-without-losing-meaning&quot;&gt;without losing meaning&lt;/a&gt;. It’s hard to write with focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example - let’s look at 2 different email service providers. MailChimp and Constant Contact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lots of software companies fail to explain what they &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; do. In this example, just take a look at homepage of each company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/coxvusqpxcvxq_small.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mc-v-cc.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mailchimp.com/&quot;&gt;MailChimp&lt;/a&gt; uses three words. &lt;em&gt;Send better email.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.constantcontact.com/overview-home?s_tnt=56380:4:0&quot;&gt;Constant Contact&lt;/a&gt; goes for a 13 word explanation. &lt;em&gt;Successful marketing starts here. Bring your marketing together with the Constant Contact toolkit.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which is more clear? MailChimp explains exactly what you do with their software. It’s dead simple. So simple even my mom uses it - not kidding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Constant Contact leaves you wondering what’s in their toolkit. The word marketing is redundant. This is where it starts? And it comes together? It sounds confusing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This doesn’t mean MailChimp is automatically better than Constant Contact. Or you shouldn’t do business with Constant Contact. It just illustrates the importance of a simple message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it were easy to write less more people would do it. We wouldn’t have sentences like &lt;em&gt;“We bring innovation to strategy through Strategic Interrogation, Engineered Creativity and Directed Research” - via &lt;a href=&quot;http://designjargonbullshit.com/&quot;&gt;designjargonbullshit.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. More words might sound elegant to you, but it just makes other people scratch their head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suck it up. Write short. Use small words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A few good words can be worth a thousand pictures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Roy Peter Clark, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/How-Write-Short-Craft-Times/dp/0316204358&quot;&gt;How to Write Short&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pool switched to a long course. Instead of 25 meters, it’s now 50 meters. The 16 laps are the same distance as the 32 laps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My workout didn’t lose any purpose when you cut it in half.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It got better.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/cut-it-in-half/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/cut-it-in-half/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Best Answer is a Question</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A family friend of mine is trying to sell his house. He went through the long process of updating the home and putting it on the market. And he finally got an offer from a couple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The deal was in place, but then it vanished. You’ll never believe the reason why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People rarely tell you the truth. Big lies. Little lies. White lies. It happens all of the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Individuals are honest only to the extent that suits them, including their desire to please others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Dan Ariely, Predictably Irrational&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about all your daily interactions. It could be with a loved one, co-worker, client, customer, or the mailman. These conversations are built on assumptions and biases. In other words - lies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to you combat people’s dishonesty? The best answer is with a question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My father over-communicates. He asks question after question. When my brother and I were growing up, this used to annoy us to no end. My brother even called it the Spanish Inquisition. Torture by questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How was your day?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you like that class?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you ok?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where are you going?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How are you going to get there?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I understand why he asked all those questions. We were teenagers and didn’t want to tell the truth. We didn’t even want to talk. But the only way for him to get an idea of what was going on in our brains and to get closer to the truth was through questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a simple task we often ignore. Emails are ended with please let us know if you have any questions. Instead of us asking the real questions that will create a conversation that reveals the truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My role in customer support is to have answers. But the real answer is in questions. The guidance you give is never one size fits all. Because people are different. That’s why I’ve learned to ask questions like these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why do you ask that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why do you say that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does this make sense?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does that sound fair?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does this help answer your question?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does that help?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is this what you’re looking for?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s preventing you from doing that today?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can you explain that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s interesting, can you tell me more?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why was the offer pulled from the house? The couple’s kitchen table wouldn’t fit in the kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You and I know that’s not the real reason why. But what is?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best answer is a question.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/best-answer-question/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/best-answer-question/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Transcribe &amp; Publish with Draft</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As a student intern with sports information, I used to have to transcribe coaches and players quotes for the media. I used an old recorder to rewind the tape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was full of frustration. But part of me misses transcribing those quotes. You can miss something even if you didn’t like it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when I learned &lt;a href=&quot;http://draftin.com&quot;&gt;Draft&lt;/a&gt; lets you transcribe any media inside its simple online word processor - I wanted to give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;heres-how-you-can-transcribe-and-publish-a-public-folder-using-the-web-app&quot;&gt;Here’s how you can transcribe and publish a public folder using the web app.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this example, lets say we want to transcribe this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SGKcr4pmReU&quot;&gt;Youtube video from Newcastle&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out this short screencast below. There is no audio, but follow the steps once you login to your Draft account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;//fast.wistia.net/embed/iframe/nutyqgboac?videoFoam=true&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; class=&quot;wistia_embed&quot; name=&quot;wistia_embed&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; oallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; msallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;//fast.wistia.net/assets/external/iframe-api-v1.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;transcribing-tricks&quot;&gt;Transcribing Tricks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Draft lets you loop the actual audio or video. This example is only 16 seconds, but you get the idea. This is extremely helpful because it eliminates the step of having to pause the video, type, restart the video, pause again, and continuing typing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;publish-the-folder&quot;&gt;Publish the folder&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once finished you transcribing, you can name your document and move back to the folder you created. Then with one click, you can publish the folder and add any subdomain you choose .withdraft.com. It’s that simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other cool things you can do is change the css by embedding a override.css file in the folder and host more than one document using an Index file. Check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://ninjasandrobots.com/draft-announcements-job-board-draft-sites-editor-flow-and-more#draft-sites&quot;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Draft is built by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/natekontny&quot;&gt;Nate Kontny&lt;/a&gt; and you should give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/transcribe-draft/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/transcribe-draft/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Grow?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The line was out the door. And stretched down the steps through the parking lot. A bizarre sight. A long line extending outside a small building in the middle of the country on a farm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mapleviewfarm.com/locations/country-store.php&quot;&gt;Maple View Farm&lt;/a&gt; has been in operation for over 50 years. You can get milk and butter fresh from the farm. And they happen to make delicious ice cream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which is the reason all these people, me included, stood in line for over 40 minutes. Just for a cone of Carolina Crunch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Behind me in line, the question was asked several times. Why don’t they open other stores? The line is too long, why not grow?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People believe that big is better. We’re obsessed with growing and expanding things. Our bank accounts. Our companies. Our customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a perfect world, everything would be bigger. Because bigger is better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“If the world were perfect, it wouldn’t be.” - Yogi Berra&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scratch your head. But that quote is so true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cameron_Indoor_Stadium&quot;&gt;Cameron Indoor Stadium&lt;/a&gt; seats less than 10,000 people. It has no air conditioning. It’s over 70 years old. Duke has won 4 National Championships while calling Cameron home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Isn’t it time Cameron Indoor grow?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it was any bigger it wouldn’t be the home court advantage that it is today. Students wouldn’t be able to suffocate the opposing team. And they wouldn’t have home winning streaks that span across seasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cameron Indoor Stadium is just the right size.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine if you could grow your bank account, company, or customer base double its size tomorrow. Would it be perfect?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Far from it. Because you would have a slew of other challenges and problems. When you obsess over growth, you fail to realize what you have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And sometimes what you have is just what you need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maple View Ice Cream opened 2 retail locations in the area a few years ago. They grew. And then they shut both of them down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because a line out the door and 40 minute wait is just the right size.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-grow/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/why-grow/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Focus is Saying No</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;People describe it as sketchy. Ghetto. Lame because you can’t even get a mixed drink. The bathrooms are gross. And it smells like urinal cakes inside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a bar in my hometown. And I love it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://hesnotherenc.com/&quot;&gt;He’s Not Here&lt;/a&gt; is the definition of a dive bar. It’s the oldest bar in Chapel Hill, NC for one reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Focus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bar has its own beer garden. It’s fantastic on a warm spring day. It attracts all types of people. Even the sketchy ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The downstairs is an old automotive garage - and it still feels and smells like it too. Kegs are shoved in a corner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bathrooms are disgusting. And the ceiling upstairs is low. When it’s packed, you feel like you can’t breathe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t own a liquor license. It serves just beer and champagne. But there in lies it’s focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Blue Cup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s famous for one item on its menu. A 32 ounce plastic cup that you can fill with beer. There is only one place you can get a Blue Cup. And it’s He’s Not Here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“When you think about focusing, you think focusing is saying yes. Focusing is about saying no. And when you say no, you piss off people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The result of that focus is really great products. Where the total is much greater than the sum of the parts.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Steve Jobs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He’s Not Here could have changed. It was &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.indyweek.com/indyweek/storied-bar-hes-not-here-is-for-sale-a-remembrance/Content?oid=2743700&quot;&gt;for sale on Craigslist&lt;/a&gt; in 2012.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bar could have added food. Undergone renovations to eliminate the smell. And started to deter the sketchy people who frequented it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It could have got it’s liquor license. They even joked about it on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Hes_Not_Here/status/451160250201419776&quot;&gt;April Fools&lt;/a&gt; this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it didn’t do any of these things. It’s never changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a town where coffee shops and breweries thrive, the oldest bar remembers when this town was just a village.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since 1972, He’s Not Here has been full of focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Focus is not about trying hard. Doing more. Or saying yes. It’s about saying no. Taking a stand. And having a point of view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re not pissing people off, you’re not focusing.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/focus/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/focus/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Name Calling</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Users. Clients. Customers. Subscribers. Leads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever been called one of these?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your startup doesn’t have users. Your agency doesn’t have clients. Your store doesn’t have customers. Your blog doesn’t have subscribers. And your website doesn’t have leads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stop the name calling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are people. Husbands, wives, mothers, fathers, brothers, and sisters. And these people are the most important aspect to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because people don’t care about how much you know, until they first know that you care about them. People have needs. They need to be loved, recognized, and respected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should strive to make every person glad that he or she interacted with you. Because when you are helpful and useful to people, a funny thing happens. They return the favor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make people glad. Reward them. And before you know it, people start rewarding you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because no one wants to be treated as a user. People want to be treated like people.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/name-calling/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/name-calling/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Do Less</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We live in a copycat world. We use the internet as a crutch for any problem we try to solve. And the result is lots and lots of noise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of trying to be original, we resort to what others have done before. For example, new companies describe what they do with hollow explanations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We’re the Wikipedia for Alcoholics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We handcraft brand experiences to enable brand advocates &amp;amp; consumers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Making the world a better place through constructing elegant hierarchies for maximum code reuse and extensibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The consequence? By trying to outdo the competition, you end up with bloated solutions full of bullshit.  Or more adequately defined:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Superfluous, unneccessary&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Cluttered, clunky, or needlessly complex&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Intentionally deceptive or insincere&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Excrement of an adult male bovine mammal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Brad Frost, &lt;a href=&quot;http://bradfrostweb.com/blog/post/death-to-bullshit-at-creative-mornings/&quot;&gt;Death to Bullshit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The classic example here is Microsoft and Apple. People wanted several different things out of a computer operating system. And that’s what Microsoft gave them with Windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It led to a swollen operating system that people struggled to find useful. There were even &lt;a href=&quot;http://winsupersite.com/article/faqtip/windows-7-tip-of-the-week-remove-the-windows-features-you-dont-need&quot;&gt;articles&lt;/a&gt; written about removing features you don’t need. Windows became bullshit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What people really wanted out of an operating system was Macintosh OS X. It does less than Windows, and is twice as useful. It’s beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s 3 other examples to illustrate why you should do less than competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-just-want-the-forecast&quot;&gt;1. We just want the forecast&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Weather Company, yes that’s actually its name, has evolved into a news site that does everything but give you what you want. The weather. It’s full of mindless information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An upstart, &lt;a href=&quot;http://forecast.io/&quot;&gt;forecast.io&lt;/a&gt;, delivers exactly what you want - the weather. Forecast.io does less than &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.weather.com/&quot;&gt;weather.com&lt;/a&gt;, and that’s why people love it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meteorologists get paid to be wrong. I didn’t think you could screw up that up. But The Weather Company accomplishes this in spectacular fashion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://img.svbtle.com/ydqznjcrlmwffw.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/ydqznjcrlmwffw_small.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;weather-example.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-just-want-to-see-the-menu&quot;&gt;2. We just want to see the menu&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.in-n-out.com/menu.aspx&quot;&gt;In-n-out&lt;/a&gt; makes delicious hamburgers. And their menu is stupid simple. Double-double. Cheeseburger. Fries. Shake or drink. And if it’s too plain for you, they have a dynamite &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.in-n-out.com/menu/not-so-secret-menu.aspx&quot;&gt;secret menu&lt;/a&gt; with 6 additional options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;McDonalds has grown into a me-too brand. They do everything from salads to snacks to coffee to Shamrock Shakes. You have to explore their menu. I’m serious, McDonald’s has a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mcdonalds.com/us/en/full_menu_explorer.html&quot;&gt;full menu explorer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;One-hundred and eighty-seven&lt;/em&gt;. That’s how many items are on the McDonald’s menu explorer. In-n-out lets you choose from 11 total options, and they keep 6 of them a secret. 11 is not greater than 187, but it’s better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://img.svbtle.com/z60emnhjyq4da.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/z60emnhjyq4da_small.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;menu-example.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-just-want-to-write&quot;&gt;3. We just want to write&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google is a behemoth of a company. I use several of their products on a daily basis. But I find writing in Google Docs is full of distractions. Unnecessary features that make me feel like Microsoft Word just moved to the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A simple approach is &lt;a href=&quot;https://draftin.com/&quot;&gt;Draft&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/natekontny&quot;&gt;Nathan Kontny&lt;/a&gt;. It gives you only what you need and makes it pleasant to write. There not a slew of superfluous buttons, just the canvas to put your thoughts down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://img.svbtle.com/qz1syrc7v2lq3w.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/qz1syrc7v2lq3w_small.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;writing-example.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google believes it’s giving you everything you need to write online. Except I don’t need a ruler, add ons, and print icon. Draft is the closest experience to writing on a physical piece of paper. It’s amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t do more than the competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because when you &lt;a href=&quot;https://gettingreal.37signals.com/ch02_Build_Less.php&quot;&gt;try to outdo&lt;/a&gt;, you’re thinking behind. And never getting ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/do-less/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/do-less/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rankings are Book Covers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In high school, I remember wrapping my textbooks with a paper bag. The covers protected the books, so schools didn’t have to buy new ones every year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the outside you couldn’t even tell what was inside the book. Geometry or physics or spanish. Rarely did you write the subject on the cover. You decorated it. Left it blank. Or covered it in comics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cover was more interesting than the contents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rankings are book covers. We rank things. Lots of things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bcsfootball.org/&quot;&gt;Teams&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.timeshighereducation.co.uk/world-university-rankings/2012-13/world-ranking&quot;&gt;Universities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://images.businessweek.com/slideshows/2012-09-26/americas-50-best-cities#slide1&quot;&gt;Cities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rankings fascinate us. We rely on a rank to tell us what is better. We don’t have the time to rank ourselves, so we depend on others. We trust computers, people we’ve never met, and history to pull rank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A ranking is a number. This number is based on lots of data. Or so we’re told. Opinions and biases fuel rankings. A number doesn’t tell us anything real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bcsfootball.org/&quot;&gt;Computers ranked&lt;/a&gt; Notre Dame ahead of Alabama in 2013. &lt;a href=&quot;http://articles.chicagotribune.com/2013-01-08/sports/ct-spt-0108-bcs-notre-dame-alabama--20130108_1_bcs-title-eddie-lacy-alabama&quot;&gt;Roll Tide beat the Irish 42-14&lt;/a&gt; a month later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.timeshighereducation.co.uk/world-university-rankings/2012-13/world-ranking/institution/dartmouth-college&quot;&gt;Dartmouth College&lt;/a&gt; is number 124 in the 2012-13 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.timeshighereducation.co.uk/world-university-rankings/2012-13/world-ranking&quot;&gt;World’s University Rankings&lt;/a&gt;. The Ivy League school features &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Dartmouth_College_alumni#Pulitzer_Prize_winners&quot;&gt;11 Pulitzer Prize&lt;/a&gt; as alumni.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://images.businessweek.com/slideshows/2012-09-26/americas-50-best-cities#slide8&quot;&gt;Phoenix, AZ&lt;/a&gt; is America’s 44th Best City. Yet 1.4 million people call it home and many more &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.visitphoenix.com/index.aspx&quot;&gt;tour the city&lt;/a&gt; on vacations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t judge a book by it’s cover. And don’t judge anything by it’s ranking.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/rankings/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/rankings/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Characters of Competition</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Your competitor tomorrow may be completely different from your competitor today. It’s out of your control. What’s the point of worrying about things you can’t control?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Jason Fried and David Heinemeier Hansson, &lt;a href=&quot;https://itun.es/us/4Lfgz.l&quot;&gt;Rework&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Competition is all around you. A competitor might be a company in your industry, your favorite sports team’s rival, or the candidate that applies from the same job as you. But there are far more characters of competition than competitors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Characters of competition are hidden. Take these 3 examples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;losing-a-sale-to-a-competitor&quot;&gt;1. Losing a sale to a “competitor”&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two companies could offer the same solution. Let’s go with IBM and Apple. Both sell computers. The consumer, named Carl, buys an IBM. Apple could obsess over the loss an attribute it to IBM building a better computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, Carl didn’t buy an IBM because it was a better computer. Carl just got laid off from his job and needs to support his family. The MacIntosh computer is priced higher than IBM. The character of competition is Carl’s budget - not that IBM is better at building computers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;your-favorite-team-loses-a-recruit-to-your-rival&quot;&gt;2. Your Favorite Team Loses a Recruit to Your Rival&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You love UNC basketball. But the top recruit in the nation, Wally Pipp, just signed a letter of intent with your hated rival Duke. Duke must be the better program, have the better coach, and be the better team in a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not the case. Wally Pipp did not choose Duke because its better than UNC. He chose Duke because a returning player, that plays his position, broke his ankle and is out for all of next season. It doesn’t even have to do with coach, program, or academics. Playing time is lead role in the competition for the recruit. And it just so happens it lies with Duke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;you-lost-the-job-to-a-more-experienced-candidate&quot;&gt;3. You Lost the Job to a More Experienced Candidate&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It must be the experience. John has 6 years experience, and you own 4. If you had more experience, you would of gotten the gig. But that’s not why you lost the job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John is the brother in-law of the hiring manager. John is familiar, and it’s why he was chosen for the job. The hiring manager delivered a favor and hired John. And not you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You weren’t competing against John. You were competing against familiarity. This character of competition is undefeated. Because it’s not what you know, it’s who you know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice in these 3 examples - all could obsess over the competitor. But it’s never worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because the characters of competition change everyday. Your competitor tomorrow is not your competitor today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/competition/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/competition/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Listening to What People Do</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Almost every weekday morning this past summer, I went to my local YMCA to exercise. When entering the gym, you stop to grab a key from the YMCA staff to put your things in a locker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are hundreds of different locker keys. Like most people, I am a creature of habit and I want to choose the exact same locker every time. Locker key 161. After two days of choosing locker number 161 - the YMCA staff member started to listen to my habit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day when I sped down the stairs towards the locker room, the YMCA attendant grabbed locker key 161 and handed it to me all in one motion as I entered the locker room. No words even exchanged - she knew exactly what I wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By listening to what I do, she saved me maybe all of 15 seconds. But the emotional feeling that she paid attention and knew exactly what I wanted without me asking - powerful. It made me come back again and again. Because I knew the YMCA cared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A month later, I again went down the stairs towards the lockers. She was gone. And the new locker attendant listened to what I said, but not what I did. I had to ask for locker key 161 everyday, and he never noticed or remembered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few months later I cancelled my membership. The price was a factor, but the emotional reason was about the locker key. The expectation evaporated. YMCA cared about me, but removed the feeling of connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Retention, the data said, was driven by emotional factors, such as whether the employees knew members’ names or said hello when they walked in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/081298160X&quot;&gt;Charles Duhigg, The Power of Habit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Duhigg tackles the idea of habits with a parallel example of the YMCA in his book. The YMCA tabbed a social scientist, Bill Lazarus, and a mathematician, Dean Abbott, to learn more about retaining their customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The data found people go to the gym for a human connection. Not to exercise. People go to the YMCA for social reasons - to meet a friend. And when they meet a friend, they are much more likely to keep coming back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the locker attendant grabbed locker key 161 without me saying a word, she made a connection with me. It was familiar to see her, and it kept bringing me back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until she left, and the experience became foreign. Not familiar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Empathy is motivation. And as a listener, empathy is your &lt;a href=&quot;http://lewishowes.com/podcast/simon-sinek/&quot;&gt;greatest skill&lt;/a&gt;.  Because there are two ways to listen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You can listen to what people say, sure. But you will be far more effective if you listen to what people do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2014/03/two-ways-to-listen.html&quot;&gt;Seth Godin, Two Ways to Listen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/listen-to-what-people-do/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/listen-to-what-people-do/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Is One Number Enough?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have the privilege of speaking with several business owners and marketers each week. These are people devoted to selling more online. One of the most popular questions I receive -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What’s a good conversion rate?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A tough question to answer. It’s like asking what’s a healthy weight? There is no one size fits all answer. A healthy weight for Shaquille O’Neal and Tina Fey is no where near similar. The same is true for business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Statistics are used much like a drunk uses a lamppost - for support, not illumination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Vin Scully&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no silver bullet metric.  One number never tells the whole story. Take a sports and business example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In baseball, people measure everything. If you can record it, then there is a statistic for it. In 2013, UNC left-handed pitcher Tate Parrish appeared in 20 games out of the bullpen - the sixth most on the team. That’s 28% of the team’s 71 games. It seems like a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Parrish only threw 6.2 innings. That’s all of 20 outs. In comparison, there are 540 outs in 20 games and over 1900 outs in 71 games. While he pitched in 28% of the team’s games, he only had a hand in less than 1% of the team’s outs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because Parrish is a left-handed specialist and often just threw to one batter at a time. The “appearances” statistic is misleading on its own, but when you added in innings pitched - we can all see clearly now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two popular online businesses - let’s call them Sam’s Sandals Shop and Gary’s Golf Store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sam’s Sandals Shop has a 10% conversion rate. For every 100 visitors, 10 make a purchase. Gary’s Golf Store has a 3% conversion rate. For every 100 visitors, 3 make a purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which business is more successful? 10 is greater than 3. Sam’s Sandals Shop is more successful. But that’s not how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The average order on Sam’s Sandals Shop is $5. In this example, he makes $50 off of 10 conversions from 100 visitors. Gary’s Golf Store has an average order value of $300. The 3% conversion rate nets Gary $900.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gary’s Golf Store generates 500% more revenue than Sam’s Sandals Shop, despite have a conversion rate less than 7%. Conversion rate on its own is not just misleading, it’s careless. Because everyone would choose Gary’s Golf Store in this scenario.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what’s a good conversion rate? The best answer is a question. Because you can never judge anything off just one metric.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One is the loneliest statistic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/one-metric/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/one-metric/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Not Good Enough</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I wanted to help. In one of my old jobs, we needed a designer. As a small company, we were spread thin. And I took the reigns on the design project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not a designer. Not even close. I worked hard, stayed up late, and tried to effort my way through the work. It flat out stunk. It wasn’t good enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is when I learned a valuable lesson. You can’t be good at everything. It’s a humbling process to discover the skills you’re not good at doing. But it’s necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what do you do when you’re not good enough?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/3ResTHKVxf4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all strive to do good work. When you’re not good enough, don’t hide it. Accept it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fight through it and keep working. There is no such thing as an overnight success. Take the story of Michael Jordan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leroy Smith, a 6’7” sophomore, made the Laney High School over his classmate Michael Jordan in 1978. Jordan was so driven to improve his craft that he used Smith as motivation to succeed. In fact, when he checked into hotels at a professional, Jordan used the name ‘Leroy Smith’ as an alias.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a lanky guard at UNC, he made the first of what we would be several game winning shots in the 1982 National Championship game. When it was time for the NBA Draft a couple years later, Jordan was again passed for a taller player.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Hakeem Olajuwon was selected first overall by the Houston Rockets, the Portland Trialblazers were on the clock. Legendary coach Bob Knight recalls a conversation with Stu Inman, the General Manager of the Trailblazers, who insisted his team needed a center. Knight replied, “So play Jordan at center!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inman and Portland took Sam Bowie, and passed on Jordan. The rest is history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He could of quit when others thought he wasn’t good enough, but Jordan never stopped working on his game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“My father used to say that it’s never too late to do anything you wanted to do. And he said, ‘You never know what you can accomplish until you try.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Michael Jordan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re probably not going to be the next Michael Jordan. But it doesn’t mean you should just quit. Improvement takes time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re not good enough, fight through it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/not-good-enough/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/not-good-enough/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Write a Cover Letter that gets You an Interview</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Never confuse movement with action.” - Ernest Hemingway&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the greatest writers of all-time points out the difference between faking it and living it. As millennials, we switch jobs like we switch between mobile devices. And the first step to finding a new gig is a cover letter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The job market has never been more competitive. With the adoption of social media, we all have living and breathing resumes. A static piece of paper is trumped by a robust online presence. It’s the age of building your personal brand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-the-purpose-of-a-cover-letter&quot;&gt;What is the purpose of a cover letter?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all honesty, it would make more sense if it was called something else. It’s an outdated term that confuses the people who read them, write them, and ask for them. Job applicants dread writing them and companies rarely take the time to read them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think of a cover letter as a menu. It should entice the hiring manager to want to learn more about you, much like a good menu directs you on what to eat. A stale menu or one with too many options leaves you confused. A well-written cover letter states exactly how you can help an employer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cover-letters-take-time&quot;&gt;Cover Letters Take Time&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mistake I used to make was to spend less time on my cover letter than on my resume. I thought of cover letters as a nuisance and sometimes I didn’t apply or even include one with my application. The main reason for this mentality?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I was lazy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I refused to devote the time of actually crafting a cover letter and rationalized. Because I thought I could spend all this time and not even get an interview, or the job even. After bouncing around jobs for the last 5 years, I’ve realized the cover letter is your chance to make an impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What makes a cover letter stand out from others? Action trumps movement. Don’t just submit a cover letter. Craft one. Let’s take a look at 2 different examples below from my experience in applying for jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;which-one-would-you-rather-read&quot;&gt;Which one would you rather read?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/b3jpcqmnvv46q_small.png&quot; alt=&quot;Cover_Letter_examples.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, yes that is Hulk Hogan on the right in an actual cover letter I submitted that got me a job. Second, how could you not choose the one on the right. It looks more interesting because it stands out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just as the objective of a sentence is to get the next one read, the objective of a cover letter is to further yourself in the job process. To get a call back and make sure they remember who you are. It’s no longer about information. It’s about attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;action--movement&quot;&gt;Action &amp;gt; Movement&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyone can research a company today. It’s so easy to find information online. You can read reviews of organizations before even applying and find out exactly who you are sending your resume and cover letter to. You can stalk employees on social media profiles. Technology changes everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ease of finding information means attention is at a premium. Your cover letter has to capture the attention of whoever is reading it. Even if it is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://consumerist.com/2012/01/31/tips-for-beating-the-resume-reading-robots-of-doom/&quot;&gt;machine&lt;/a&gt;. Because it’s not what you know. It’s who you know. And in this case how they will remember you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pdfs-dont-capture-attention&quot;&gt;PDFs Don’t Capture Attention&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PDFs are plain annoying. There has to be a better way to represent yourself than an 8.5 x 11 piece of paper. It’s commonplace to submit a resume and cover letter that way, but it doesn’t mean you have to comply with it. You know what beats a PDF?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;emails-capture-attention&quot;&gt;Emails Capture Attention&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above resume on the right was sent through &lt;a href=&quot;http://mailchimp.com/?utm_expid=68055709-37.mcqmwYpNS-qCBhoizOPPKg.0&quot;&gt;MailChimp&lt;/a&gt;. You could attach some PDFs to your email or deliver one directly to the hiring manager’s inbox. And even though we glamorize inbox zero, email is still one of the most effective means of communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good thing MailChimp strives to send better email. An account is free for up to 2,000 subscribers. The beauty is no one is subscribed and you can send a personalize message directly to the person who is going to hire you. Yes, you have to submit the email addresses and answer that they want to receive email from you to comply with spam laws, but it’s worth the risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MailChimp isn’t the only option either. You track opens with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.getsignals.com/&quot;&gt;Signals&lt;/a&gt;, use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yesware.com/&quot;&gt;Yesware&lt;/a&gt; for templates, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://rapportive.com/&quot;&gt;Rapportive&lt;/a&gt; to understand your contacts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;better-email-better-cover-letter&quot;&gt;Better email, Better cover letter&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A text email converts better than html, but I believe in customizing the email. And it’s worked for me. Here’s 3 reasons why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;it-shows-your-skills&quot;&gt;1. It shows your skills&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/ddssw4tb7wp4iw_small.png&quot; alt=&quot;Cover Letter HTML Emails.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I coded my email on my own and successfully used MailChimp to deliver it. This shows I know some level of HTML and CSS, plus I can competently use one of the most popular email marketing programs on the market. You don’t have to code your own, using a template in MailChimp or sending a brilliant text email is just as impressive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t matter if your job doesn’t involve email marketing. You’re showing your value. Because you understand the skills it requires to deliver a well-crafted email. And the prospective company needs as many skills as they can get.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;you-know-if-it-was-actually-read&quot;&gt;2. You know if it was actually read&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most overlooked advantage of sending your cover letter through a service like MailChimp is you can see if it was opened. The software delivers reports on open rate, what links were clicked, and how many times it was opened. As mentioned above there are several great alternatives. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.getsignals.com/&quot;&gt;Signals from Hubspot&lt;/a&gt; is easy to use web app that tracks email opens and clicks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last thing you want is for no one to read your cover letter. It’s a risk you take, but you can stop wondering if they opened it or not. This allows you to follow up in a smarter way than just blinding sending your resume again or mustering up the courage to call the employer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;answer-the-tough-questions-right-away&quot;&gt;3. Answer the tough questions right away&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/iivaut1bsstfqw_small.png&quot; alt=&quot;Cover Letter examples.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chances are your resume will raise questions. It turns out when you lazily submit a cover letter, employers easily judge your resume and wonder if you’re right for the job. But if you take the time to answer the questions you know a company will ask in your cover letter, it saves time for all parties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can address this in a plain 8.5 x 11 sheet of paper. Or you can take the time to use images and carefully frame a message to answer the right questions. It pays off to change the context with an email. Because it’s not about getting your cover letter read, it how your cover letter makes the potential employer feel. Put in the effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;still-skeptical&quot;&gt;Still skeptical?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Thanks for putting so much effort into your cover letter. It is refreshing to see someone who understands the point of a cover letter. You explained why you are a good match for this specific situation. It takes time to do it for each job application, but it’s the only way to get noticed.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After my first try of sending a cover letter like this, I received this response. I didn’t get an interview and frankly I was not exactly qualified for the position. But that response validated the action I took in crafting this cover letter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Remember action beats movement. Start sending a cover letter that gets you an interview.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/cover-letter/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/cover-letter/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nervous Means Alive</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“It’s okay to be nervous, it means your alive.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The advice you receive from your parents is endless. Be safe. Take care of yourself. Sit up straight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re rarely ready to learn at the same time your parents are ready to teach you. The advice falls on deaf ears. You don’t even hear it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then one day, you start believing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to get terribly nervous before rec league basketball games. I felt like I was a 10 year old kid getting ready to go play Michael Jordan in front of thousands of people. I thought the nerves meant I was just afraid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It means your alive, my mother would say. It was comforting, but I really didn’t understand it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until, I believed it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re getting ready for a job interview, a date, a cold call, a game - you get nervous. You think about all the ways you could fail. Instead of using that energy to your advantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning to sell yourself or your ideas is not easy. And a major obstacle is overcoming your nerves. But you will continue to fail, if you let your nervous feeling take over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Everyone gets nervous. Everyone. If they say they don’t, they’re either lying or they’re sociopaths. The trick is to use the nerves to trigger adrenaline. Let them lift you up to a higher level. A better you.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.coughter.com/pdf/coughter_sixty_vol12.pdf&quot;&gt;Peter Coughter, The Art of the Pitch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your body reacts the same when you’re nervous &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; excited. It’s simple. If you’re nervous, tell yourself you are excited. And then use that excitement to perform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because Mom was right after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feeling nervous? It just means your alive.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/nervous/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/nervous/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Experience</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Experience separates the old from the young. The good from the bad. The disciplined from the reckless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But how do you get experience?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember asking myself this question. Like a lot of my peers, I lost out on several jobs because of one thing. Experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a deflating cycle. Why do you need experience to get experience? If you had experience, you wouldn’t need experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is experience is all around you. It comes from the most unlikely places. You just have to open your eyes and embrace it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;know-why-and-where-you-are-going&quot;&gt;Know why and where you are going.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t just do whatever makes you happy. That is empty advice. Max Temkin and the founders of Cards Against Humanity shared their values and beliefs. Be funny and stay independent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Temkin’s business experience prior to building a best-selling board game? A summer at Radioshack. Now he shares his &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.maxistentialism.com/post/47207276845/kickstarter&quot;&gt;experiences&lt;/a&gt; with others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“We had no idea what we were doing, but we had vision and values.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://creativemornings.com/talks/max-temkin&quot;&gt;Max Temkin, Creative Mornings Talk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;connect-the-dots&quot;&gt;Connect the dots.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gary Vaynerchuk is a salesman. He’s built a multi-million dollar wine business, wrote best-selling books, and now runs a successful creative agency. Before all that, he came from zero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He went from selling baseball cards to selling wine. Because he connected the dots of his past experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Frank Thomas, Ken Griffey Jr., Wayne Gretzky. Silver Oak, Caymus, Chateau Lafite. Same shit.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?
v=lsqaqRBTj_s&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&amp;amp;t=6m7s&quot;&gt;Gary Vaynerchuk, The Cain Conversation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;put-in-the-time&quot;&gt;Put in the time.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Louis C.K. started doing standup in 1984. As a writer on the Conan O’Brien Show, he once played a tree in a sketch. He didn’t all of sudden become great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took patience and persistence to win Emmys. It took doing things for free. It took experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“A 55 year old garbage man is a million times smarter than a 28 year old with 3 PHDs. Especially smarter than him. The garbage man is 55. He has &lt;em&gt;experience&lt;/em&gt;. Things have happened to him.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://youtu.be/rXcWeFn-YYM?t=1m46s&quot;&gt;Louis C.K., Older is Smarter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want more experience, share what you believe. Try new things. Volunteer. Work for nothing. Be patient. Ask for help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/experience/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/experience/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Drunk on Data</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You can make numbers say whatever you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2010, I kept score of almost 100 baseball games. As a sports information director at UNC and a press officer for USA Baseball, I saw my fair share of statistics. It’s here I learned an important lesson.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Statistics are like a bikini. They show a lot, but still cover up some very vital information.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can measure nearly anything in baseball. Batting average, runs batted in, saves, earned run average, on-base percentage, and more. All for a game as simple as - 1, 2, 3 strikes you’re out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a humid April night in Clemson, SC. The Friday night matchup pitted both team’s best pitcher against each other. Prior to the game, the opposing radio crew wanted to get my perspective on the UNC starter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The crew stared at the stats. 4-2 record. Solid strikeout-to-walk ratio. But then they got lost in the numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0-2 in his last 3 starts against ranked teams? One crew member quipped, “he struggles against good competition. And our offense is even better than the ranked teams he’s faced.” Clemson, ranked in the top 25 at the time, featured a player that led the league in home runs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could of pulled out more numbers and tried to state my case. A win-loss record of a pitcher is about as meaningful as your fifth grade report card. But all I said was the numbers are misleading in those 3 games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The crew chuckled and dismissed my comment, hypnotized by the numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast-forward a few years later. I work for an analytics company. We help online businesses measure all aspects of their commerce. I interact with businesses owners and entrepreneurs who rely on these numbers everyday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last month, I found myself in an interesting conversation. I began to ask a customer to compare the metrics and data available today to when he first started in e-commerce 15 years ago. I couldn’t even finish my sentence, before he cut me off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“There is so much of it out there today, I feel like I have data coming out of my ears. Data is important, but it can be too much of a good thing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He went on to explain how we’ve all fallen in love with data. We measure stuff because we can, not because we should. The numbers drive too many of our decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re data drunks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to that muggy April night. The UNC pitcher single-handedly led his team to victory. And 3 years later, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.goheels.com/ViewArticle.dbml?ATCLID=208697160&quot;&gt;Matt Harvey&lt;/a&gt; was the starting pitcher in the MLB All-Star game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could rave about how he shoved a complete-game or struck out 15 batters that night. But as the radio crew that only believed the stats a few hours earlier admitted . . .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Numbers won’t tell you the whole story.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Because numbers can’t talk.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/drunk-on-data/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/drunk-on-data/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Time</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Time is money.  Billable or non-billable. Timelines and timetables. Measured by timecards and timesheets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is overtime and downtime. Daytime and nighttime. Dinnertime and lunchtime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you waste time. If you don’t have time, make time. Your pastime might be playtime. In the springtime or summertime or wintertime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In due time, you might have free time. It’s been a longtime since bedtime. You wish you had the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time is sensitive. You need more time. Facetime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Halftime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One at a time, you can save time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In your lifetime, it might be showtime. Anytime. Primetime is big time. Me time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in the meantime, the first time is the last time. This time, you might run out of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you remember the time? You lost time? All the time or most of the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time flies and time crawls. In real-time. You have time to kill and time heals all wounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Timeout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is your concept of time? It’s time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time is a lot of things. It is not one-dimensional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me explain. Just give me some . . .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/time/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/time/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>